I know I should know this, darling,
but are you mad at me?
Baby. Holly.
[SIGHS]
I did something, right?
I did something bad, right?
Should I know what it is?
Or is it something
maybe you just think I did?
No, no. I did it. I did it.
It was a bad, bad thing I did,
and I'm so sorry, luv.
Holly, come on, will you?
Holly, wait. Baby...
[PANTING]
...you have to let me in on it.
Or are you waiting until we're in
the apartment before you talk to me?
[SIGHS]
Are you gonna make me
sleep in the bathtub again?
GERRY:
Oh, no, I don't know what I said.
- You said it. You know you said it.
- No, I don't know what I said...
...but I didn't mean it.
- You mean everything you say.
Sometimes I mean nothing
when I say something.
Something is never nothing.
It's always something.
Most of what I say is nothing.
Just something to say.
Men say it's just something to say
to get away with saying something...
...but they know they're saying something.
- Say what? What did I say?
You said at my mother's, you
would have a baby but I'm not ready.
To my mother! You might as well
have said I'm a lesbian.
Well, I am the only man you ever had.
Oh, I dated Timmy Harrison
for four months before I met you.
- Isn't he a woman now?
- Aah!
You told my mother
I didn't want children!
- I did not. I didn't say that.
- Yes, you did.
- Yes, you did. You said exactly that.
- I did not.
I didn't say that you weren't ready to
have a baby. I said that you wanted to wait.
Which means I don't want one right now.
- Right.
- Thank you.
Wait a minute. I'm confused.
Can I get a ruling on this?
No, you're not confused.
You're just wrong.
"Holly doesn't wanna have a baby."
We had a plan, Gerry.
To wait to have children
until we could buy an apartment...
...put 25 percent of each paycheck
into a separate joint account...
...with a 6.25 interest for 5 years.
Why didn't you tell my mother that?
Ha-ha-ha. Each paycheck?
Darling, you only just started
getting regular paychecks.
- You quit five jobs in two years, remember?
- Well, I can't work for idiots.
- They can't all be idiots.
- Yes, they can.
They can all be idiots.
And why didn't you tell my mother...
...about the business loan you and John
took out without asking me?
Oh... Aha!
You see, you... You finally said it.
- I knew that's why you're angry.
- That's not the reason.
It is not the reason.
- It is the reason.
- We should have waited.
Waited for what? What?
I've been driving limos for four years, Holly.
So John and me, we wanna start a business.
We buy a few cars, we get a few clients.
That's a career right there.
What is your problem?!
What if it doesn't work?
What if we always have to live here?
And what about what I want, huh?
You think
I wanna be a real estate agent...
...showing apartments to buy
that I can never live in?
There may be other things
I wanna do with my life.
- Okay. Like what?
- I don't know. Other things.
Then quit, all right? The job makes you
cranky at home every bloody day anyway.
- You wanna have a baby? Let's do it.
- See?
- I hate when you do that.
- Hah. Do what?
"Let's have a baby." La-la-la!
In a five-floor walkup we can barely move
in. I'd change diapers on the windowsill.
You have to have a plan. You can't act like
everything's just gonna work out by itself.
Why do I have to be
the responsible grownup who worries?
Why can't I be the cute, carefree
Irish guy who sings all the time?
Because you can't sing
without making dogs bark.
[HOLLY GRUNTS]
Look, Holly, people have babies
with no money all the time.
If you're so worried about it, why don't
you stop buying designer clothes?
I buy everything on eBay.
It doesn't count when you're wearing
Marc Jacobs from Minneapolis.
[DOOR OPENS]
Do you want to have a baby?
- Do you?
- Yes, I do.
- See?
- See what?
I know what you're really saying
even when you don't say it.
You mean the two conversations thing.
The one we're having
and the one you think we're having.
You said that to my mother because you're
mad at me for not wanting children yet...
...and because I'm no fun anymore and
we don't have enough hot, nasty sex...
...because I'm always bitching about bills.
Why don't you just be honest and say it?
Say what you mean.
All right.
I wish we had more hot, nasty sex.
Or the other kind is fine.
What you're really saying is this
isn't the life you wanted, is it?
Well, that's not what I'm saying.
Is that what you're saying?
And what if this is it, Gerry?
What if this is all there is to our life?
- What do you mean?
- It means this is it.
We're a married couple
who own a limo company...
...who may or may not have children,
end of story.
- Well, what other story do you want?
- I don't know. L...
What do you want, Hol? What?
Because I'm tired
of trying to figure it out.
You want a bigger apartment?
I'll take a second job.
You want a child, you don't want a child.
What?
I know what I want because
I have it in my hands right now.
Do you?
Do you know what you want?
Because you better tell me now
if I'm not it.
Or what? You gonna leave?
- You want me to leave?
- Lf you wanna leave.
- Don't use me as an excuse.
- I'll leave if you want me to.
Then leave if you wanna go.
- Don't push me.
- You wanna leave, just say goodbye.
Oh, that's me bollocks!
- Stop acting bilingual.
- Oh, kiss me arse.
Kiss mine in English!
[DOOR SLAMS]
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
Are we finished now, luv?
Can I come back?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, luv. Ahhh.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I said the wrong thing
to your mother.
God, I still get nervous around her.
I still think after nine years,
she doesn't like me.
I know I'm being stupid.
No, you're not being stupid, baby.
She doesn't like you.
Really? And I thought deep down,
she really loved me.
No, she doesn't.
I was 19 when we got married.
And you corrupted me
with sex and charm...
...and the longer it takes you to make your
fortune, the less sexy and charming you are.
Hmm.
What? What are you looking for?
Me balls. They were hanging there
a minute ago.
My mother said it was a mistake marrying
you because I loved you too much.
"It won't last."
I don't wanna make any mistakes, Gerry.
Well, you're in the wrong species, luv.
Be a duck.
[MO ANING]
My baby.
We're not a mistake
just because we don't have any money.
And we are gonna last.
You know how I know?
Because I still wake up every morning...
...and the first thing I want to do
is see your face.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I see people buying bigger apartments
and having babies.
I get so afraid sometimes
our life's never gonna start.
No, baby.
We're already in our life.
It's already started. This is it.
You have to stop waiting, baby.
And Hol, you can't keep eating
me head off, telling me to leave.
I'm not going anywhere.
[SIGHS]
I'm not your dad.
Or don't you know that yet?
[CHUCKLES]
I should get my shoes.
They're all over the place.
They're gonna think I don't love them.
[SIGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING O VER STEREO]
[HOLLY LAUGHING]
HOLLY:
Whoo!
Shake it, baby.
Do the stomach shake.
HOLLY:
Whoo!
Oh! Ow! Aah! Ooh!
[MIMICS LEPRECHAUN]
My eye! I'm blind.
Oh, I just wanna lick
your little Glaswegian chocolate.
Okay, okay. I can't believe
I'm in love with a leprechaun.
[CHUCKLING]
- Oh, wait. The light. You were up last.
- The light?
- No.
- You were up last.
But I'm not up now, am I?
Baby, look, I'm injured. My eye.
God. A pain in me hole.
That's a good girl.
Come on, get back to bed
or I'm gonna start without you.
[THUD]
Aah! Shit.
- You okay?
- Shit, no! My toe! Oh! Ow!
I tell you what. Someone should get a light,
that side of the bed. It's ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
- I'll get my next husband to do it.
- Oh, come here.
Next husband. Oh-ho-ho. Next husband.
Come here, you.
I'm sorry I lose my mind sometimes.
- Did it hurt you? Let me look.
- Will you shut up and kiss me, okay?
GERRY:
You crazy bitch. Pain in me hole.
[HOLLY LAUGHING]
Oh, Daniel, we forgot those Thanksgiving
decorations. Will you take them down?
Sure, Mrs. Reilly.
Where do you want them?
Patricia. In the skinny closet.
Have you got the key?
No, I don't.
I'll make you a set next week.
And ask Gerry's drivers
to close the curtains, will you?
Sure.
MAN: Go ahead.
WOMAN: Thanks.
[GUESTS CHATTERING]
- John.
- What?
- Oh, Denise.
- Hi.
- Oh, it's good to see you.
- Do I have to help?
- No, you do not have to help.
- Good.
- Sharon, you look great.
- Hi.
- Hi. This is good.
- So do you.
- Am I late?
- No. This is gorgeous.
Wait till you see Gerry.
You're gonna die.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Well, as Gerry would say,
let's get this party started.
Gerry Kennedy did not want a lot of words.
He preferred music.
He was a unique young man...
...as you can see by the urn he had
designed by the love of his life...
...his wife, Holly.
His life may be over for now,
but we can still hear it.
He lives in us forever in our hearts...
...like his favorite song.
[THE POGUES' "FAIRYTALE OF NEW YORK"
PLAYING O VER STEREO]
THE POGUES [SINGING]:
Got on a lucky one
Came in eighteen to one
I've got a feeling
This year's for me and you
So happy Christmas
I love you, baby
I can see a better time
When all our dreams come true
- You're a bum, you're a punk
- You're an old slut on junk
Lying there almost dead
On a drip in that bed
You scumbag, you maggot
You cheap, lousy faggot
Happy Christmas, your arse
I pray God it's our last
The boys of the NYPD choir
Still singing "Galway Bay"
And the bells are ringing out
For Christmas Day
Aww.
Mama, how you doing?
- Ciara.
- Oh, sis, good to see you.
- Oh, good to hold you.
- Oh.
Hello, Gerry.
[MUSIC PLAYING O VER SPEAKER]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[ALL LAUGHING]
- Hi, I'm Denise.
- Matt.
- I love your tie.
- Oh, thanks.
- Are you single, Matt?
- Yes.
- Are you gay?
Okay.
Did Holly call his parents?
Why aren't they here?
I did, I spoke to the mother.
His father's just had another operation.
He's not supposed to travel.
So why didn't she come alone?
I mean, it's Ireland, it's not Japan.
It was their only son.
Don't ask me.
- Hi.
- I like your chain.
- Thanks.
- Denise.
- George.
- Are you single?
- Yes.
- Are you gay?
- No.
- Are you working?
You make a ravishing widow, sis.
Thanks.
I'm so glad you're here, but it's so far.
I would've understood.
No, I'm done with Australia.
Besides, Gerry wrote me I had to.
He wrote you?
Yeah, a couple of months ago.
Probably because of Mom.
He knew I'd have melodrama
for her to play with...
...while you pull yourself together.
Can I get you anything?
Mm.
- I'm sorry about your loss.
- Thanks.
How did he die?
- A brain tumor.
- Nice!
So that's a great looking urn.
I wish I were that creative.
I buried my dog in a stereo box.
[STIFLED CHUCKLE]
It's not the same.
[CHUCKLING]
- I love your suit.
- Thanks.
- Are you single?
- Yes.
- Are you gay?
- No.
- Are you working?
- Yes.
- Denise.
- Sam.
Oh.
[APPLAUSE]
When Gerry and I went to a bank
to apply for a business loan...
...I was a little nervous. Gerry told me:
"Relax, these people are never
gonna give us the money...
...so we might as well have some fun."
[CROWD CHUCKLING]
No, don't clean.
No, I have to do something.
I can't talk anymore.
- Wanna stay with us while your sister's here?
- No.
I think...
You know, I think I should be home.
I think I need to be...
...home.
- Well...
...this is your home too, you know.
But that's good. Get back on your feet.
That's a good thing.
[SIGHS]
[PANTING]
[PHONE BEEPS]
[RECORDING]
Hey, it's Gerry at Enniskerry Limo.
Leave a message.
[DIALS PHONE]
[PHONE BEEPS]
Hey, it's Gerry at Enniskerry Limo.
Leave a message.
[PHONE RINGS]
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
PATRICIA [O VER ANSWERING MACHINE]:
Holly? It's Mom. Are you all right?
Are you showering? Don't make me worry.
SHARON:
I'm worried you're not calling me back.
I know it's hard, honey, but don't lock
yourself in. It's been over a week.
- I'm here, okay?
DENISE: Hey, it's Denise.
Listen, I buzzed your apartment.
Nobody's heard from you.
Where are you? All right, call somebody.
I love you.
[O VER TV]
I'll make him pay for it. I will.
Whatever you might do,
I can do more...
... because I know how to fight
better than you.
Why can't I be Bette Davis?
GERRY'S VOICE:
All right? I mean, the job...
... makes you cranky
at home every bloody day anyway.
You wanna have a baby? Let's do it.
HOLLY: See? I hate when you do that.
GERRY: Hah. Do what?
HOLLY:
"Let's have a baby." La-la-la!
In a five-floor walkup
we can barely move in.
You can't act like everything's just
gonna work out by itself, Gerry.
Why do I have to be the responsible
grownup who worries?
[O VER TV]
If you're killed, I'll be free.
If I'm killed, it really doesn't matter.
If we both die, good riddance!
JOHN ELDREDGE:
Go ahead, crash it. Crash it!
[SIGHS]
[TV CLICKS OFF]
Gerry, get the light.
It's your turn.
Mmm.
[GUITAR PLAYING]
GERRY [SINGING]:
I just want to see you
When you're all alone
I just want to catch you if I can
I just want to be there
When the morning light explodes
On your face it radiates
I can't escape
I love you till the end
- Do all Irishmen sing?
- Heh.
I'll love you till the end
Ah. Only the really well-hung ones.
I can't fall asleep alone.
I'm right here, baby.
I had a terrible dream.
Don't tell me.
Gerry, I don't wanna go back to work.
- What should I do?
- Quit.
Stay here with me.
[MO ANS]
I don't have a plan, Gerry.
That's okay, luv,
your plans never work out anyway.
Hmm.
That's true.
[JUD Y GARLAND SINGING
"THE MAN THAT GOT AWAY" O VER TV]
HOLLY [SINGING ALONG]:
And all because of the man
That got away
No more his eager call
The writing's on the wall
The dreams you dreamed
Have all
Gone astray
The man that won you
Has run off and undone you
That great beginning
Has seen a final inning
Don't know what happened
It's all a crazy game
No more that all-time thrill
For you've been
Through the mill
And never a new love
Will be the same
Good riddance, goodbye...
[TV CLICKS OFF]
CIARA:
Whoo!
ALL:
Happy birthday!
[BOTH BLOW PARTY HORN]
You're 30!
Hey, Holly...
...these were falling out of your mailbox.
What is that smell?
I wasn't expecting company.
Mom, don't clean.
- I'm not. I'll just organize the garbage.
- We did try to call first.
- Are you drunk?
- No.
- Do you wanna be?
- Ciara.
What happened to your head?
Pimple.
- You're not showering?
- You always squeeze it too hard.
- What is that smell?
- It's me, all right?
Hey, hey, hey. Don't be like that.
- Like what?
- Like the only Ionely widow in Gotham City.
I'm just... exhausted.
Yeah, well, what are you doing,
two shows a night?
[STIFLED CHUCKLE]
You know, if you want us to leave,
that's fine...
...but you do know that at some point,
this all has to stop.
All right.
Just give me a second, okay?
I'll get cleaned up.
- Okay, troops, let's sweep the area.
- Yes.
I haven't called the office. Are they mad?
Nah. There's no rush.
Even Larry said, "Take all the time you
need. The job is there when you're ready."
That was nice of him.
- He's an asshole.
- He's still an asshole.
Do you think it'll be all right
if I stop my life right here?
Become the Miss Havisham
of the Lower East Side.
Never leave my apartment till I'm old.
- Sit in my wedding dress.
- Which you never had.
- With an old piece of wedding cake.
You gotta be rich to be insane, Hol.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
Losing your mind
is not a luxury for the middle class.
CIARA: I'll get it.
- That's so not fair.
No, it's not.
Holly? Something's been delivered for you.
What is this?
- I don't understand. Did you do this?
- No.
JOHN:
Wait a minute.
- John, tell me the truth. Did you do this?
- No. I did nothing, I swear.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
GERRY [O VER TAPE RECORDER]:
Hey, baby. Surprise.
I know this probably feels
a little bit morbid...
... but I just hate the idea
that I'm not gonna be there...
... to see you freak out over turning 30.
I mean, it kills me not to be there.
Heh-heh. That's funny.
- No, it's not.
- Okay. No, it's not.
You're gonna be so impressed.
I have a plan, baby. Can you believe it?
I've written you letters. Letters that will be
coming to you all sorts of ways.
I waited till your birthday. I figured
you weren't stepping out of the house...
... for a while. Letter number one
will be arriving tomorrow.
Now, you must do what I say, okay?
Okay?
Don't try to figure out
how the letters are coming.
It's too brilliant and it'll ruin my plan.
Just go along with me on this.
Because the thing is,
I just can't say goodbye yet.
So for starters...
... I want you to get dolled up,
and just go out and celebrate tonight.
Go out with your girlies.
I hereby free you from a party with
your family, especially your mom.
Oh, man, your mom's there, isn't she?
Mm. Shit.
Sorry, Patricia.
It isn't that I don't love you...
... but she needs to get a little crazy.
So have a slice of the bloody cake...
... put on your dress
and get out of the apartment.
- Denise, make a plan.
- I'm on it!
- I'll help.
- Just leave me with John, okay?
And know that wherever I am,
I'm missing you.
Happy birthday.
I love you.
[WHOOPING, CHATTERING]
- Come on.
- Look, it's a private gay club.
Yes, but we are on the list.
My colorist called and he's gay.
Gay colorist in New York?
Like sand on the beach.
Listen, Crystal. Don't mess with her.
- He's a very good colorist.
- Uh-huh.
And she's the princess of Finland.
And she's here on matters
of critical political importance.
And she's here to extend
the hand of friendship from Finland...
...to homosexuals...
MAN: That's us!
...throughout the tri-city area.
[MEN WHOOPING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
What?
[CROWD CHEERING]
HOLLY:
Thanks.
Great. You're fired.
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING O VER SPEAKERS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Okay. "Snaps" is the name of the game.
The name of the game is "Snaps."
Make sure you pay attention.
[SNAPS]
Ready?
[SNAPS THREE TIMES]
Have you got it?
Mariah Carey?
[ALL CHEER]
I don't get it.
- Paul.
- God, he's been dead, like what?
- Fifteen years.
- Unbelievable.
- Can you believe that?
- You remember Steve?
Steve was so sweet.
He was a good guy.
- Honey, don't be so Miss Doom and Gloom.
- You'll be fine.
Yeah, don't worry about it.
CIARA:
"Snaps" is the name of the game.
The name of the game is "Snaps."
- Do you hear me?
- Yeah.
[SNAPS TWICE]
Ready? Keep looking.
PATRICIA AND JOHN:
Derek Jeter!
- Come on. No.
- How?
SHARON:
This is a stupid game.
[WOMEN LAUGHING, CHATTERING]
Sorry.
What are you doing?
Trying to figure out
why God killed my husband.
Well, if you need any help with that,
let me know.
- Ow!
- Sorry. Heh.
- Daniel?
- Yeah.
So why do you think?
Your husband died?
Maybe you're being punished
for something.
- What?
- Being too happy? Too beautiful?
I don't know.
God can be a pretty jealous guy.
I don't believe that. I've never been
too happy. I'm not too beautiful.
I think you're hot.
Sorry, I have a syndrome.
I don't really have a filter.
I don't pick up on social cues.
You mean you're rude?
Yeah, but now it's a disease
I can take medication for.
They have pills for rudeness?
I know. And they can't figure out
the Middle East. Go figure.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Hey, you're Irish.
Maybe it's an Irish curse or something.
Well, Gerry and I did love the Yankees...
...which was pretty much
against our religion.
Well, there you go.
That explains a lot, actually. I love the
Yankees too, and I lost my fiancée last year.
Really?
Yeah, she slept with my best friend.
She left me.
Oh...
My best friend was a woman.
Oh.
Her last words to me were, "I'd still
be with you if you weren't a man."
And I'm like:
"Well, castrating me is definitely the first
step toward achieving that particular goal."
It's still my fault. I introduced them.
I always had this fantasy about making love
to two women at the same time.
Except in my fantasy, I was still
in the bed for the second and third time.
- Sorry.
- Then this'll make you feel great.
The best friend that my ex-fiancée slept
with was my ex-ex-fiancée...
...and she was my business partner, and
we started the business with my money.
So I ended up losing the business,
my partner and my fiancée.
How'd you get over that?
I went through, like,
a major hooker phase all year.
But that didn't help.
No, it helped a lot.
I just started to run out of money.
It's actually a lot cheaper to date.
Do you think that you're gonna ever find
another woman to love?
No.
No, I think I repel
the women that I want the most.
That's not true.
No?
[VOMITING]
HOLLY:
Thank you, Daniel.
You can start closing up downstairs.
Right.
[MO ANS]
[CELL PHONE RINGTONE
PLAYING LOUDLY]
What do you want?
- Oh, good. A friendly voice.
HOLLY [O VER PHONE]: Oh.
What happened last night?
Lemon drops and tequila, my friend.
The moment where a 30-year-old body
does not recover quite as fast...
...as a 29-year-old body.
Stop screaming at me.
- Are you working?
- Hell, no.
But I told him we're gonna start next week.
We'll go out starting Monday.
- Is that okay?
- No, I was planning on...
...staying in bed and dying today.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, you can't.
You gotta go check the mailbox,
remember?
Call me immediately.
GERRY: Save yourself bruises
and buy yourself a bedside lamp.
And remember, a disco diva
must look her best.
Go buy yourself a knock-out outfit. You'll
need it for when my next letter comes.
Need it for what?
And I know you hate your job,
but I'll help.
Look for a sign. You'll know what to do.
P.S. I love you.
[LIGHT SWITCH CLICKING ON AND OFF]
HOLLY [WHISPERING]:
I still know you're around.
You're still here, aren't you?
MAN:
So who lived here before?
A family. They're having another baby.
So do you have any children?
Three. Girls. Teenagers.
That's nice.
Uh-huh.
Ted, Sharon says there's
another offer on the table...
...and we have to move on this.
SHARON: I think if you offer another
hundred grand, they'll back down.
Well, maybe we should talk about it.
We don't have time, Ted.
We have to tell her today.
We didn't wanna go over...
I know, but we love this apartment,
and it is what it is.
There's nothing else.
This is what an apartment costs.
- We're already beyond our cap.
- We'll make it work...
- Think about another area.
- I am not living in Brooklyn.
- Will you listen to him?
BOTH: What?
He's obviously worried about this.
- Look at him. He's pale.
- Hol.
Who are you to tell me
how to talk to my husband?
You shouldn't push this on him
if he doesn't want to.
I'll push what I want on him.
He's my husband.
I want this apartment.
- Say no, Ted.
- It is amazing that you are still talking.
- Don't listen to her.
- Ted, she's being a tyrant.
She's got your balls on one of those
things that cling back and forth.
- You know?
- Yeah.
- You bitch.
- Brat.
- Shut up!
- You shut up!
No, you shut up!
I will end you, and when I do...
- You know what? I'll tell you...
- No. No. No. Okay, tell me.
He's my husband, I'll talk to him the
way I want to. I'm not living in Brooklyn!
VICKY: Do you know who I am?
HOLLY: What's wrong with Brooklyn, lady?
[DOORBELL BUZZING]
Are you Holly Kennedy?
- Lf I am, will you sing?
- Yes.
- No, I'm not.
- Please don't make this an issue.
- I gotta sing and deliver a letter.
- A letter? What's the song?
- "Yah Mo Be There."
- Just give me the letter.
- I could get reported.
- By the leprechaun union?
You know, I was in an off-Broadway play
with Al goddamn Pacino.
I don't need this shit.
You want the balloons?
- No.
- Fine.
[OPENING ENVELOPE]
You bastard.
There's no way I'm doing this.
GERRY: Yes, you are.
- No, I'm not.
- Oh, yes, you are.
- Oh, no, I'm not.
Remember the last time?
[SINGING]
All you wanna do is ride around, Sally
CROWD [SINGING]:
Ride, Sally, ride
All you wanna do is ride around, Sally
CROWD:
Ride, Sally, ride
GERRY:
Yeah!
One of these early mornings
You gonna be
[CROWD CHEERING]
Wiping those weeping eyes
Those weeping eyes, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
GERRY:
Thank you very much.
Oh, my God.
[COUGHS]
GERRY: Whoo!
- One more!
Okay. I guess it's time to give
somebody else a chance here now.
Who wants a shot?
Anybody else here willing to give it a go?
[CHATTERING]
Yourself? No? Young lady.
Come on. Don't be shy.
- What about Holly?
- Stop it.
Holly. I don't know about that, John.
Holly's my wife, by the way.
My beautiful wife.
And I do... I love Holly, I do.
But she would never have the guts...
CROWD:
Oh!
...to do something like this.
Oh, no.
In fact, she ate me head off
about coming out tonight.
You know, she had
a long day at the office.
[GERRY SNORES]
Ah. She'll never do it.
Yep.
[CROWD CLAMORING]
GERRY:
Oh, you think so?
You think she'd get up here?
Okay, I'll bet you 100 dollars...
...she doesn't get up on this stage.
CROWD: Oooh.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Make it two.
[ALL CHEERING]
[LAUGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
[CHEERS, WHISTLES AND APPLAUSE]
- What is she doing? What is she doing?
- Ha-ha-ha.
That's my wife, the surpriser.
[SINGING]
How can I put this in a way
So as not to offend or unnerve
Holly!
There's a rumor going all around
That you ain't been getting served
All right.
They say that you ain't you know what
In, baby, who knows how long
It's hard for me to say what's right
When all I wanna do is wrong
Get off
Twenty-three positions in a one-night stand
I'll only call you after if you say I can
Get off, let a woman be a woman
And a man be a man
Get off
If you want to, baby
Here I am
Here l...
ALL: Oh!
- Oh, God!
[SIREN WAILS]
[GERRY SIGHS]
Do you mind coffee?
How do you feel? You look good.
I'm sorry, baby, but I have to say
you were really good before...
My nose is broken, Gerry.
My ankle is twisted. Happy?
- Are you mad at me?
- I didn't wanna go out...
...and you made me.
I hate karaoke
and you forced me to go up there.
Come on, honey. It was nobody's fault.
Oh, come here, baby. Give me a...
Give me a kiss.
[SIGHS]
Well, how long are you gonna be mad for?
HOLLY:
I never let him off the hook.
Anytime I was mad,
I made him feel bad.
I was mad when we
left the house that night.
I was mad at him because our apartment
was too small. So stupid.
Baby, you were married.
Married people make each other
feel like shit on purpose sometimes.
It just feels good.
Gerry knew you were crazy about him.
He told me all the time.
Well, I wish I would've told him that night.
So tell him now.
It's slightly dirty. Just slightly.
[MUSIC PLAYING, INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Ooh.
He's delicious, isn't he?
You could serve coffee on that ass.
Do you have to be so vulgar about men,
like they're pieces of meat?
I'm sorry, John. I forgot you're sensitive
about your flat ass.
JOHN:
Hoh.
You know, Denise,
that's why you're not married.
- Ahem.
- Women act like men...
...then they complain
men don't want them.
Oh, is that why? Oh.
Okay. Because I thought
it was something different.
I thought it was because
I thought that I deserve the best.
And he's out there.
He's just with all the wrong women.
And let me be clear.
After centuries of men looking at my tits
instead of my eyes...
...and pinching my ass
instead of shaking my hand...
...I now have the divine right
to stare at a man's backside...
...with vulgar, cheap appreciation
if I want to.
- Well said.
- I thought so.
New York City, how we doing? Huh?
- Hey, guys, we're here!
GROUP: Yay!
Give a warm welcome
to our next singer.
Rumor has it this is her return engagement.
Put your hands together...
...for Holly.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
[SIGHS]
This is for you, Gerry, you son of a bitch.
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
[SONG INTRO PLAYING]
[SINGING]
I just wanna tell you
Nothing you don't want to hear
All I want is for you to say
Oh, why don't you just take me
Where I've never been before?
I know you want to hear me
Catch my breath
I love you till the end
[APPLAUSE]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER, LAUGHTER]
Okay, let me get this straight.
You're straight, you're single,
and you own your own business?
It's my own club.
I'm doing a big renovation right now.
- It'll open in the spring.
- Mm-hm.
I could show it to you if you want.
It's over on Tenth Avenue. Wanna go?
Great.
Yeah. Let me just do one thing first.
Mm.
What's my name?
- Tom.
- Where have you been?
With all the wrong women.
Hmm.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hey, Gerry. You lost weight.
Thanks for inviting me.
[CHUCKLES]
You're a terrible singer.
Yes, I am.
- I'd be really embarrassed if I were you.
- Did you take your medication today?
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
No, I thought I'd come here instead.
[CHUCKLES]
Say, I'm feeling kind of hungry. You feel
like getting a bite or something to drink?
No, I'm... I don't think so.
- It's all right.
- Thanks.
I don't mean to throw this at you,
but what do women want?
I can't figure it out.
They want us to ask.
They don't want us to ask. They want us
to make a move, not make a move.
They want us to be on bottom, be on top.
Use hair products, don't use hair products.
What do you people want?
I'll tell you, but you have to promise
not to say I told you.
- L... I swear.
- Because it's a sacred secret.
Sacred secret.
- You ready? You sure?
- Yeah. I think so.
Come here.
[WHISPERS]
We have absolutely...
...no idea what we want.
- I knew it! I knew that! Son of a bitch!
- Ooh!
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah.
Look, if you ever just wanna get out...
...just do anything, just...
I'll wait for your call.
And just so you know,
I'm not looking for a thing right now.
- I'm just flirting in good faith.
- I appreciate that.
Maybe we can defy God...
...and go see a Yankees game.
- Yeah.
[CHUCKLES]
We'll be really weird friends,
joined by self-pity, bitterness and vomit.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
- I'd like that.
- Me too.
[MUMBLES]
GERRY: My leather jacket is for you.
I always loved the way that looked on you.
But the rest of my stuff,
you don't need it.
Make some space in that bloody
apartment for yourself. Go on.
It's time, baby.
P.S. I love you.
DANIEL:
I think you're a little bit perverted.
I mean, you bring me
to an Irish famine memorial...
...and we're eating corned beef
sandwiches. That's pretty sick.
Gerry thought it was the best way
to honor the dead.
You know, show them
how well we're doing.
I'm sorry I always bring him up.
Yeah, I'm starting to get
a little bit sick of it.
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
[CHUCKLES]
Now that's a real honest-to-goodness
couple right there.
They've probably been together
since the Flood.
We're so arrogant, aren't we?
We're so afraid of age,
we do everything we can to prevent it.
We don't realize what a privilege it is
to grow old with someone...
...someone who doesn't drive you
to commit murder.
Or doesn't humiliate you beyond repair.
It's sweet.
[CHUCKLES]
It's good, huh?
[LAUGHS]
HOLLY: Can I ask you a favor?
DANIEL: Sure.
I started bagging up Gerry's stuff.
Couldn't finish.
I think I need someone who
didn't know him to get rid of it all.
DANIEL:
Be happy to help you get rid of Gerry.
- Do you have to say it like that?
- Like what?
- What is wrong with you? Take a pill.
- Nothing. What?
What's wrong?
Nothing, I...
I've just never been alone with another
man in this apartment besides Gerry.
Want me to stand out in the hall?
You can just throw me the boxes.
No. Heh.
[CHUCKLES]
That's okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna change.
Look through stuff.
If there's anything you want...
...just let me know.
- Okay.
Mm.
I can't remember the last time
somebody held me like this.
Did you find a new husband yet?
Shut up.
[CHUCKLES]
Where have you been?
- I haven't felt you around lately.
- Oh, please.
I've been so around.
Mm.
[WHISPERS]
I can feel you hugging me.
That's because I am.
You look great.
This is the one.
[PHONE RINGS]
- Are you Barbara?
- Yes, may I help you?
I hope so.
You're his wife.
He was here?
[CRYING]
So I don't understand.
You're taking a vacation?
HOLLY:
It's a trip.
Gerry planned the whole thing
for me and Sharon and Denise.
You think it's the best time to vacation?
Gerry made all the arrangements.
I have to go.
Have you spoken to Daniel? Thought you
two were spending time together.
We're just friends, Mom.
I've stood by and not said anything about
all this, but now I think it's time it stopped.
- What do you mean?
- It's not healthy.
Gerry's not gonna be able
to keep this up forever, is he?
His life ended, and so will his letters.
You're gonna have to face
things on your own.
It was a gift from Gerry.
And how can you say that?
My husband was 35 years old.
He wasn't supposed to die.
But he did. It was awful.
It's what happens.
But his death is a part of your life now.
And you have to deal with it.
Stop saying that
like I'm not dealing with it. I am.
How? By waiting for a letter
from a dead husband?
Taking a vacation? When your father left,
I had two children to support.
- Excuse me for not having any children.
- That's not how I meant it and you know it.
Your father leaving
was just as devastating.
But I did what I needed to do
and got on with it.
- It's not the same thing.
- Why not?
My husband died. He was taken.
He didn't wanna go, he didn't wanna leave.
Yes, my husband wanted to leave.
And it's so much easier
being abandoned by choice, is it?
I've had my say.
I won't say anymore.
So where's he sending you?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
Oh, my God.
Get the bags.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh.
- All right.
- She just elbowed me.
Know what? If that's an indication of
how this trip's gonna be, I won't have it.
[DENISE AND HOLLY CHATTERING]
[GRUNTS]
Is that her bag? Is that her bag?
- Leave it. Don't take it in.
- This is ridiculous.
[HOLLY AND DENISE
CONTINUE CHATTERING]
Holly?
- This is heavy.
- I know.
SHARON:
Holly!
[SUITCASE THUDS]
Look.
[SIGHS]
"Hey, Big Mama. Make sure
my baby has a good time.
Make sure you and John do everything
you wanna do...
[VOICE BREAKING]
...whenever you wanna do it.
And make sure my baby does things.
[LAUGHS]
- I want you to take her fishing."
- Oh, God.
He's been wanting to get me
on a lake since forever.
"And be sure to give yourself
a big, sweaty pony-boy kiss from me."
Ugh. Jerk. He will never let me forget
my bachelorette party.
Joey the Pony Boy.
- Tony.
Tony, I remember him.
I bet I have a letter too.
Where would he hide one for me?
[IN UNISON]
Bedroom.
DENISE: "Denise, take Holly to Whelan's,
my favorite pub.
There's beautiful music to be heard,
beautiful people to be around.
And Denise, you're going to heaven
for being my baby's friend.
I'm making all the arrangements
up here for you.
Got a few hot men lined up. I hear
Ben Franklin's hung like a racehorse.
Love you."
- I don't know how you do this.
- Let me see it.
SHARON:
What?
He didn't leave me a letter.
Well, probably didn't love you...
...as much as us.
- Mm-mm.
[GUITAR PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER, LAUGHTER]
Oh my God, look at that. Look at that!
Oh.
Oh, my God.
Oh. Please let me buy him as a souvenir.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
- He's coming this way.
- He's coming.
How long has it been?
How long has what been?
SHARON:
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
- You're gonna go talk to him. Oh, yeah.
- Mm. No.
You just heard him.
Say how much you like it, flatter him. Go.
We don't have those in the States.
DENISE: Go, go.
SHARON: We don't make those.
- You're ready.
- Go! Do it for us. Go on.
SHARON: Where'd she go?
- What are you doing? Go ahead!
I'm an old married widow.
Oh, you've got much better stuff
than those tarts. You're experienced.
You're American. You got
foreign exotic stuff going...
There's nothing exotic
about being an American.
- He doesn't know that.
- We'll help you.
- Just take it off.
HOLLY: No, no, no!
SHARON:
Listen! You're gonna do what we say.
I'm gonna hurt you.
I'll pull your hair.
You look hot. Put your shoulders
back. Puff your hair a little.
- You're so sexy. Go.
- Yeah, you look hot. Do it!
HOLLY:
Hi.
[CHUCKLING]
I just wanted to say
I really loved your music.
You're beautiful. I mean...
I mean... Sorry.
Your music is beautiful.
Thanks... Um...
- Holly.
- William.
- You're American?
- Yeah.
And what brings you to Ireland?
Holiday. Oh, well, with my girlfriends.
- Hi.
Good. Good to have you here.
- Heh. Thanks.
- I have one more song to play.
Will you stay and have a listen?
It's an American song about a local girl.
I think you'll like it.
- Sure.
- Good.
Grand.
So I'll see you after, then?
Okay, sure.
[GUITAR PLAYING]
Em...
This is an American song
dedicated to Holly.
I hope you enjoy it.
[SINGING]
Well, I took a stroll on the old long walk
Of a day l-ay-l-ay
I met a little girl and we stopped to talk
Of a fine soft day l-ay
And I ask you, friend
Well, what's a fella to do
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
'Cause her hair was black
And her eyes were blue
And I knew right then
I'd be takin' a whirl
Round the Salthill Prom
With a Galway girl
That's a very nice jacket.
HOLLY'S VOICE:
I won it in a bet.
We were halfway there
When the rain came down
Of a day
GERRY AND CROWD:
L- ay-l-ay
And she asked me up to her flat downtown
Of a fine soft day l-ay
And I ask you, friend
What's a fella to do
'Cause her hair was black
And her eyes were blue
Enough of this.
[CROWD CHEERING]
HOLLY: Why does he want me to remember
all these things that make it harder?
It's cruel.
SHARON: I don't know, baby.
But I don't think he means to be cruel.
HOLLY:
What does he mean?
DENISE:
I don't know.
Come on, let's go.
We're taking you back.
[MOTORC YCLE APPRO ACHING]
- I think you should find William.
- No.
I left without saying anything.
He must think I'm an idiot.
Well, you're an American.
They expect us to be idiots.
Don't push her.
If she's not ready, she's not ready.
Although if memory serves me correctly,
Holly...
...the longer you go without sex,
the meaner and bitchier you get.
- Eat me.
- Hello.
[CHUCKLING]
Well, I'm really mad at Gerry.
Maybe that's why he did it. You have to
stop wanting him at some point.
When?
[WHIRRING]
[GASPS]
- Grab the pole!
- What?
- You've got a fish!
- It's a fish!
- Okay.
SHARON: Holly, grab the pole!
- Okay, I'm grabbing it! I am, I am.
SHARON: Take it out.
- Hurry it up!
- Aah!
You're not holding the ball.
Turn the knobby thing!
- Will you stop being so butch?!
DENISE: Just watch it! Oh! Ow!
- Help me!
SHARON: Do you wanna get the fish?
HOLLY: I'm trying.
DENISE: Stop! My nails are wet!
- Guys!
- Careful!
Guys, I lost...
[ALL SCREAMING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
Oh, my God.
What happened to our oars?
SHARON:
Oh, my God.
Help!
ALL:
I hate cosmetics companies.
They get you addicted to
the perfect lipstick or nail polish...
...and then six months later,
they discontinue it.
You have to buy your favorite colors like
you're storing up for the apocalypse.
That was my last bottle of this.
I think that one of us
should swim ashore...
...and it should be the one
who's already inflated.
Okay, no, that's good. Here!
[SCREAMS]
[AIR HISSING]
- There, go swim ashore.
- Was that necessary?
- You can swim ashore.
- You happy...
...I inhaled all these toxins?
- You jump in!
- Stop fighting! You're acting like babies!
- All right. Shut up!
[AIR HISSING]
Nice.
Maybe we'll eventually
drift towards the shore.
What shore? That could take months.
Better not take more than nine or else
there'll be another person on this boat.
What?
I wasn't gonna say anything
until we got back.
I'm having a baby.
[BOTH SCREAMING, LAUGHING]
A baby? Sharon, wow.
I know, I know.
- When are you due?
- March.
Oh, thank God.
You can still be in my wedding.
What?
Ah! I'm getting married.
Tom proposed, I said yes...
...and we're planning
a New Year's Eve wedding.
Aah! Gosh!
Congratulations!
[DENISE AND SHARON LAUGHING]
- You okay?
- Yeah. No. Yeah.
No, I mean, it's just... This is just
a lot of information to get in one boat.
Oh, baby, I'm sorry.
I wasn't gonna say anything
until we got back. This is your trip.
- No, no, it's okay.
- Yeah, no, me too.
But, you know, we might die here,
so I'm not going down as a spinster.
- You're getting married.
- You're having a baby.
- Oh, my God. What, are you kidding me?
- What?
- God.
- I know.
[DENISE AND HOLLY CHUCKLING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Mm.
Who's the cook?
- I am.
- Me.
- We all helped.
- Ugh.
Denise is getting married.
Isn't that great?
Sharon's pregnant. Heh.
WILLIAM: Congratulations to both of you.
DENISE: Thank you.
SHARON:
Thank you.
The food was great. I don't think
I came up for air once.
[BOTH GIGGLING]
[CHUCKLES]
You know, it got a lot darker
while I was busy.
Mm. Yeah, it gets dark at night...
...here.
You work on the lake?
Two days a week. Kind of a patrolman.
Although, I gotta say, first time
I ever had to save anyone.
I feel really badly about you having
to drive all the way back this late.
- That's enough.
SHARON: In this rain, forget it.
DENISE:
Feel free to stay till morning.
SHARON: Yeah, we have a pull-out couch.
A bed that pulls out.
Oh.
It is a long drive.
- I would love a shower.
- What a great idea!
There's one downstairs, it's fantastic.
I'll get you some linens and towels.
I'll show you.
Great. Take your wine...
[SHARON CHUCKLES]
[WHISPERING]
What, are you crazy?
DENISE:
He's staying the whole night.
He's gonna be here all night long,
all night long.
He's gonna be here all night.
[WATER RUNNING]
[SHARON AND DENISE CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING]
SHARON:
You have to get pregnant immediately.
DENISE:
Immediately. We can have kids together.
SHARON: How cute is that?
I mean, how cute is that?
I don't know, I have this weird feeling.
I feel like there's a boy inside of me.
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING CONTINUES]
[WILLIAM CLEARS THRO AT]
Oh, Jesus! Oh, sorry.
I thought you were upstairs.
I need to just get my clothes.
I'll get out of your way.
[SIGHS]
Sorry about that.
Would you like a drink?
Should I just lick it off the counter, then?
- Oh, no!
- Yeah.
Sorry, no... It's been a long time
since I've seen a man that naked.
I mean, you have a...
How about that drink?
- You're very sweet.
- Oh, God.
The last time a guy said that he followed it
up with, "But I don't date 13-year-olds."
[CHUCKLES]
Well, lucky for you, neither do I.
Cheers.
[GLASS THUDS]
[HOLLY MO ANS]
[LAUGHS]
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Hi.
Sorry. Oh, I can't do this, I'm sorry.
It's not you.
Look at me, I'm shaking.
I don't know how to do this.
Don't even know if I want to,
I haven't been held in...
Oh, never mind. I'm just screwed up.
I'm trouble. Yeah.
- I like trouble.
- Oh, no. Heh.
I don't mean "cool Pulp Fiction" trouble...
...I mean "mental case wacko" trouble.
I'm out of my league here. I mean,
I haven't had a new man in over 10 years.
I had this old one. I mean, he wasn't old.
He was just old to me
because I had him so often.
He was my husband, but he died.
[WILLIAM EXHALES]
Kissing him like that,
I'm not surprised, poor lad.
[CHUCKLING]
No, it's not gonna work.
I feel like I'm trying on a new pair of shoes
I really wanna buy, but they just don't fit.
Sorry.
All right then, how about
going barefoot for a while?
[RAIN PATTERING]
WILLIAM: There's no man, alive or dead,
who's gonna fault you for living.
You're very sweet.
He was a good man, I reckon,
your man who died.
Yes...
...a very good man.
- William?
- Hmm?
Could you drive me to Enniskerry
in the morning?
Sure.
You got friends there?
Family. Sort of.
- In-laws. I should see them.
- Hmm.
What's their name? Maybe I know them.
The Kennedys.
Not Rose and Martin?
Yeah. You know them?
You're not Gerry's Holly?
What?
Oh...
You're the girl from the pub that night.
I was in Gerry's band.
Not Billy...
...Gallagher?
- One and the same.
[GASPS]
It's... It's all right.
It's all right. Me and Gerry,
we shared everything together.
[GASPS]
Oh, no, no, no, I didn't mean it like that.
What I meant was, you know,
he wouldn't have a problem...
Well, he might have a problem
but, you know...
...there's not much
he can do about it now, is there?
Holly.
Come here. Come back to bed.
Now, let's... Let's talk.
Oh...
I heard he died.
Tumor, was it? Yeah.
You know, Gerry and I, we...
We hadn't seen each other
in a long, long while.
It's sad when that happens
to best friends, isn't it?
[SIGHS]
He... He was a wonderful lad.
It's all right, you know.
It's okay.
You know, these things...
...they happen now and again.
Not very often...
[HOLLY CHUCKLES]
...but now and again.
Would you like me to tell you
some stories about me and Gerry?
I've got plenty.
Yeah?
Okay, here you go. Come on, sit back.
You know, he was...
He was my very, very best mate.
Starting back when we were terrors
running about at 5 and 6.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, he made me laugh.
There was this time,
I don't remember how old we were...
...probably, you know, 10, 11.
We jumped on a train...
[WILLIAM TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[INAUDIBLE]
[PIANO PLAYING]
We received those packages you sent.
Come in. Come in.
Martin?
Look who it is.
Oh, well, look at that.
Come here, dear.
So nice to see you.
He was always one for writing.
Wasn't he?
Should've gone professional.
No. He did it for the love of it, Martin.
Now, where is it?
Oh, here it is.
"When Holly visits, take her
to my fort in the back yard...
...and give her this envelope."
He knew that I'd come visit you?
Hmm. Suppose he did. Heh. Martin.
All right.
It's not really a fort,
it's just a stone wall.
He used to call it that when he was little.
He goes on about other things...
...Iovely things.
He hadn't much strength in the end
though, did he?
Makes me sick to think
we weren't there when he died...
...for the funeral.
ROSE: But you could hardly walk
just after your operation.
Maybe you'll come and visit us a bit more
now that he's gone, eh?
Martin, don't put that on her.
You're under no obligation.
It's not like we're blood family.
I'd like to come visit.
And I'm sorry we didn't in the past. L...
I just thought you were angry with me
for taking Gerry away.
- She wanted you dead, you know.
- Martin, don't you dare!
No, I don't blame you.
You know, my mother, she never
quite got over the idea either.
Yeah, well, you were both so young.
And it happened too fast.
But Gerry loved you. I saw that.
I saw that.
GERRY: To my Galway Girl:
You're an angel for seeing my folks.
I told you my mom didn't hate your guts.
Well, you know, anymore.
You are now standing in my fort
where I did all my big thinking.
This is where I stood thinking about you
after the very first time we met.
You didn't look real to me at first.
I never saw so many colors
on one girl before...
... but you looked like
you belonged out there, all right.
You and all your colors.
Do you remember
the first thing you ever said to me?
I'm lost.
Oh, you didn't look lost, not to me.
So, what are you looking for out here?
Wicklow Mountains National Park?
[LAUGHS]
Wicklow Mountains National Park.
Tell me, how long you been walking for?
A few hours.
Well, you've probably been in
the national park for a few hours, then.
Oh, my God.
This is a park?
Uh-huh.
Oh.
It's so cold!
The paper said it was gonna be warm.
It is warm. I know you're lost, but
you do know you're in Ireland, don't you?
Well, I better head back. Heh.
- And where is that?
- I'm staying at a B and B in Dunlougahairy.
Dunlagohairy?
No, I think you mean Dún Laoghaire.
- Heh-heh. You're kidding?
- No. Would I lie to you?
- Dún Laoghaire?
- Dún Laoghaire.
Okay. Thanks.
You're grand.
But you're going the wrong way,
you know.
[SOFTLY]
That way?
[CHUCKLING]
Okay.
I think you quite enjoy this getting lost,
don't you?
You know, actually,
I don't mind so much, not here.
So how did you come to be here?
Oh, on my way home, college trip.
We started in Greece.
Jesus, that's a long walk.
That's a bad joke.
What are you studying?
- Art. Yeah.
- Art?
- Oh, so you're an artist, then?
- Oh. I don't know yet.
That's great.
[CHUCKLING]
Do you make anything or?
I don't know yet.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Well, good luck with that.
Oh.
You...
Would you mind if we walked together
since we're going in the same direction?
I'll stay on this side of the road.
Don't even have to talk. Just...
Just quite nice, sometimes walking
along with someone without talking...
...once you get your feet wet.
GERRY:
At first, the no-talking thing didn't last.
Before long, I couldn't get you to shut up.
But you were so cute, trying to impress me
with William Blake and all your grand plans.
I had no idea
what you were talking about...
... but I couldn't help
loving the way you talked.
"I must create a..."
Something."...or be enslaved
by another man's..." Something.
Wait, "I will not...
[GRUNTS]
I will not reason or compare.
My business is to create..."
- Something. Oh, God.
- Did you just make that up then?
No, it's William Blake,
but I completely screwed it up.
No, you didn't, you made it better.
I understood it.
GERRY:
I didn't have a clue, actually.
All I know is, if you don't figure out the
"something," you'll just stay ordinary.
And it doesn't matter if it's a work of art,
or a taco, or a pair of socks.
Just create something new
and there it is.
And it's you, out in the world,
outside of you.
And you can look at it, or hear it,
or read it, or feel it...
...and you know
a little bit more about you.
A little bit more than anybody else does.
Does that make any sense at all?
Yeah.
You're saying you want to paint socks.
Maybe.
[CHUCKLES]
GERRY:
I loved you right then and there.
HOLLY:
Hey, I like this jacket.
GERRY:
It looks good on you. Got it on a bet.
- What was the bet?
- Heh.
I was a few Guinness's
for the worse at this point...
...but a fella bet me
that I couldn't get a certain girl...
...to kiss me without a provocation.
- What girl?
- His girl.
- Oh! Ha-ha.
- Uh-huh. Ha-ha.
- How'd you do it?
- There's nothing to it, really.
A fella just has to tell a woman
the truth without words.
It's like a signal you send out.
The woman, she just picks it up.
And what's the truth?
That kissing her would be
the end of life as I know it.
Wow.
And that's true of every girl
you've gotten to kiss you?
[GERRY LAUGHS]
I could turn it on and off when I was
younger and I had no principles.
When every girl that I was lucky enough
to kiss was the end of life as I knew it.
And now?
Now I only send it out when I think
she might be the one that makes it true.
I know where I am now.
Thanks, it was really nice to meet you.
- No, I could walk you into town.
- Oh, no, it's okay.
I know where I am.
I know where I'm going.
I'll never forget this.
Your jacket.
[DOG BARKING]
No, wait!
[WHISPERING]
Wait, wait, don't move.
- What?
- Oh, yeah, it's a wild Irish dog.
- A what?
- Shh!
- You have to stand still.
- Okay.
Get close, like one person.
And if we separate, he'll feel...
...threatened and attack our vital parts.
- What vital parts? All my parts are vital.
- Shh, shh.
[BARKING THEN GROWLING]
GERRY:
We have to stand still.
Now, just let him sniff around a bit.
[SNIFFING]
GERRY:
Now wait.
[WHISPERING]
I'm really scared.
Would you put
your arms around me?
All right.
- Yeah, that's probably a good idea.
- Yeah.
[DOG PANTING]
Do you think we could turn around and
face each other without freaking him out?
Ahh... Okay. Sure.
- But let's move very slowly, okay?
- Okay.
- Ow.
- Oh, sorry.
I haven't done this in a while.
I've been seeing this boy,
but we don't do much. I don't know why.
- Maybe it's me.
- No, he's a boy who...
...doesn't know anything about kissing.
That's a man's business.
Is it?
That was the most perfect...
...perfect first kiss.
That was the second.
This is the third.
MAN:
Brody, come.
Hey, Gerry.
Yeah. How are you, Jeff?
- Hey, where you going?
- No, stay. Stay.
No, but... You have my jacket.
I know, I'm keeping it
unless we meet again.
I bet we do.
That's a bet you're gonna
have to win because...
...if we do meet again then that'll be
the end of it, you know.
The end of what?
Life as we know it.
[CHUCKLES]
- Look, I'm singing at this pub...
- No, no, no. Don't tell me.
If I happen to walk into the right one
in the right town...
...then we'll know for sure, won't we?
And if I don't...
...then that'll just be the most perfect kiss
ever created by two strangers...
...and we'll just keep it perfect
for the rest of our lives.
- What's your name?
- No, no! Wait, no, don't.
Don't, don't. No, no...
GERRY:
Life had changed as I knew it.
And now it's changed again, luv.
See, I don't worry about you
remembering me...
... it's that girl on the road
you keep forgetting.
"My business is to create.
It doesn't even matter what you do."
You told me that, remember.
P.S.
GERRY:
So go home. Go find it.
Find that thing
that makes you like nobody else.
I'll help.
Look for a sign.
[PHONE RINGING]
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
PATRICIA [O VER MACHINE]: It's Mom.
Sharon called, said you're home.
SHARON: Where are you?
PATRICIA: Call me.
SHARON: You haven't returned my calls.
Come to my first baby doctor's appointment.
DENISE: What is going on?
Nobody's heard from you...
- ... my maid of honor. Call me.
SHARON: Call me.
GERRY: If you need to find any job
to get by, be realistic, luv, all right?
DENISE: I cannot believe
you are not calling me back!
GERRY:
You can't be a secret agent...
... and there's no such thing
as a vampire slayer.
DENISE: I'm getting married. Where are you?
SHARON: Pick up the phone!
PATRICIA:
His death is a part of your life now.
DENISE:
I am so mad at you!
[TV PLAYING]
[O VER TV]
Shh. There she is.
[STOPS FILM]
Great shoes.
[PHONE RINGING]
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
DENISE:
Okay, this message is for Holly Kennedy.
Please tell her, her friend Denise...
... is getting married December 31 st
and she's not invited. Okay?
How about that? You're not invited.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
DENISE:
Look at this. It needs to be tighter!
WOMAN:
All right, I will do whatever you want...
...but I'm not so sure, I mean, I think...
No, listen, your bust looks absolutely right,
because let me tell you something...
...you don't want to look too busty.
Yeah, well, see, although, you know,
my breasts are beautiful and firm...
...they do often have a mind of their own
and they can go off in different directions...
...without adult supervision.
So could you please just take it in just
a quarter-inch? Just a quarter-inch.
- Okay.
Could you give us...
Excuse us for a minute, please?
- Sure.
- Thanks.
You look beautiful.
Well, I could've used some help.
This is the twelfth dress
I've tried on. So...
I'm sorry.
Well, you were supposed to be my maid of
honor, but of course I didn't hear from you.
Sharon feels too conspicuous since
she's popped. So, guess what?
I had to ask Tom's 51 -year-old sister...
...who looks like Jerry Springer
and doesn't like me...
...all because my best friend couldn't
stand me being so happy.
Why? Why is that?
Because our lives were moving on and you
weren't the center of attention anymore?
- Yes.
- Really?
- It was awful and I'm really sorry.
- Oh, no, I'm so sorry, honey.
No, I'm so sorry.
You were right and I was wrong.
God, I'm such a bitch! I'm sorry!
I was so crazy mad.
I hope you can forgive me.
Oh, you know what, it's not too late.
You can still be a bridesmaid with Sharon.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Can I ask you a favor?
- I want to make your wedding shoes.
- My shoes?
What'd you turn into, Geppetto?
Oh, my God! These are gorgeous!
I've been taking a class. It just happened
out of the blue. I really love it.
Oh, my God!
HOLLY:
They're one-of-a-kind.
You'll be the only bride in history
to wear them.
Love that!
Oh, God, Holly!
This is like shoe art.
They're gorgeous! We have to
show these to someone.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
HOLLY:
I feel like Gerry's guiding me.
I mean, shoes! I love shoes but I never
thought about it.
You look so great.
Thanks.
- Course, I look great too, right? Ha-ha.
- Yes.
When all this started happening,
you're the first person I wanted to tell.
Isn't that funny?
That's hilarious. Any way we can stretch
this lunch out into a dinner?
I'm going to change the subject.
- How are you?
- I'm good. Things are good.
I've got some, some ideas for the future,
some possible business prospects.
I think about you all the time.
That's a little too much information,
I guess.
Yes.
But you did say you were
thinking about me.
Because you've been a real friend
through this all.
So, you haven't thought about me
in the nude?
No.
- Not once?
- No.
- Not even without my shirt?
- Gerry, stop it!
Daniel.
I'm Daniel.
Sorry.
You think you'll ever feel about
somebody the way you felt about Gerry...
...or do you have to wait for a letter
to figure that out?
Where you going?
I really like you...
...but I can't be the invisible man.
I'm tired of being the shoulder.
I want to be another body part you need,
you know? I wanna be...
...the bad guy.
I want a woman to go crazy over me...
...and then I wanna use her up
until she's ruined for all other men.
- You don't wanna do that.
- No, I don't wanna do that, but I would...
[SIGHS]
I'd like to date a woman
who actually likes men.
I'd like to be somebody's Gerry.
It's all right.
Honestly, it's not your fault, it's mine.
I didn't plan on feeling something for you,
it just sort of happened.
So I'm sorry about that.
Is your guest coming back?
- No.
- Just you on your own, then?
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
Take a break, will you?
- Mom!
- What's the matter?
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SOBBING]
Come on.
What happened?
When... When Daddy left...
...I was 14 and I said:
"That's it, never again. No man..."
And then I meet Gerry.
This wonderful man happens to me
and then... And then...
And then he died!
- What was the point?
- I know, honey.
I'm so angry I could kill somebody!
I'm alone and...
...it doesn't matter what job I have,
or what I do or what I don't do...
...or what friends I have. He's not here.
I'm... I'm not here.
- I mean, you're alone no matter what.
- That's right.
[SOBBING]
You know, I didn't come here for you
to give me some bullshit honest answer.
Why can't you lie to me just once?
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
- I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
- Shh. Come on.
Let's go for a walk.
PATRICIA:
Your father and I used to come here.
They had dances.
Well, not really dances.
We'd come with radios and cigarettes...
...and drink beer and listen to Jimi Hendrix.
I bet you've had a hard time walking into
a room full of people on your own, right?
Yeah, I know that.
I know what it is not to feel like you're in
the room until he looks at you...
...or touches your hand, or even makes
a joke at your expense...
...just to let everyone know
you're with him.
You're his.
God, that man could make me laugh.
Daddy?
[LAUGHING]
I don't ever remember you laughing.
Well, that makes me sad...
...because I did.
I did.
Did you hate Gerry because
he reminded you of Dad?
A little.
[SIGHS]
You know the worst thing for a parent,
second after losing a child?
Watching your child head for
the same life you had...
...and you can't stop it.
It's a terrible, helpless feeling.
Makes you angry all the time...
...and I've been angry...
...a very long time.
[SIGHS]
I'm exhausted.
Do you think we'll ever see Dad again?
No, sweetheart.
Never.
So you have to stop waiting.
You?
I have to say I was impressed by how
he worked everything out ahead of time...
...every delivery schedule,
the mailbox key...
Getting that leather jacket out
of your apartment wasn't easy...
...with you acting like Miss Havisham.
He made me promise.
I couldn't say no.
I told him I didn't think
it was good for you, but...
...I couldn't say no.
It's the last one...
...so all alone or not...
...you gotta walk ahead.
Thing to remember is...
...if we're all alone,
then we're all together in that too.
It helps me sometimes.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
DANIEL [O VER MACHINE]:
Hi, it's Daniel.
Remember what I said in the restaurant?
Well, please forget it word by word.
They're gonna build
a new Yankee stadium.
I don't know why I said that.
I'm making small talk. I hate small talk.
I hate the people who make small talk.
I should... I should stop. I'm stopping.
Shit!
[HANGS UP]
Gerry?
[FOOTSTEPS]
DANIEL:
My uncle can get us in anytime we want.
He turned the lights on for us.
HOLLY:
It's amazing...
You sure?
It's okay.
DANIEL:
"Dear Holly, I don't have much time.
I don't mean literally, I mean, you're out
buying ice cream and you'll be home soon...
...but I have a feeling this is the last letter.
Because there's only one thing
left to tell you.
It isn't to go down memory lane
or make you buy a lamp.
You can take care of yourself
without any help from me.
It's to tell you how much you move me.
How you changed me.
You made me a man
by loving me, Holly...
...and for that I am eternally grateful.
Literally.
If you can promise me anything,
promise me that whenever you're sad...
: : :or unsure: : :
...or you lose complete faith...
...that you'll try and see yourself
through my eyes.
Thank you for the honor
of being my wife.
I'm a man with no regrets.
How lucky am I?
You made my life, Holly,
but I'm just one chapter in yours.
There'll be more.
I promise.
So here it comes, the big one.
Don't be afraid to fall in love again.
Watch out for that signal
when life as you know it ends.
P.S., I will always love you."
Have you thought about this?
About me, I mean?
Have you?
Yeah.
- This isn't gonna work, is it?
- No way, no how!
- Damn!
- Oh!
[LAUGHING]
Oh, wow.
I mean, that was like kissing my sister.
- I'm so relieved!
- Ha-ha-ha.
I got this letter and I thought he must have
been feeling self-sacrificing...
...but he's really full of crap.
If he meant it, he'd give me a sign.
- I hate signs.
- Then I got your message on the machine.
[SIGHS]
Weird, bitter friends?
Forever.
[SIGHS]
What's wrong, friend?
It's Gerry.
It's been a year...
...and I don't feel him
around me anymore.
I don't think he's here anymore.
I think Gerry's gone.
[WHISPERS]
He's really gone.
HOLLY:
Dear Gerry, you said you wanted me...
... to fall in love again...
... and maybe one day I will,
but there are all kinds of love out there.
This is my one and only life...
... and it's a great and terrible
and short and endless thing...
... and none of us come out of it alive.
I don't have a plan except
that it's time my mom laughed again.
She's never seen the world.
She's never seen Ireland, so I'm
taking her back to where we started.
Maybe now she'll understand.
Mom?
William?
Hello, you.
You back for another visit?
How long?
I don't know.
Oh, um... This is my mom, Patricia.
Hello. This is me father, Patsy.
You've dropped your sweets, luv.
Mustn't do that around these parts.
Pretty woman like you,
a fella could take it the wrong way.
[LAUGHING]
[PATSY LAUGHING]
So I'll see you around, then?
Yeah.
HOLLY: I don't know how you did it,
but you brought me back from the dead.
I'll write to you again soon.
P. S...
[WHISPERS]
Guess what.