Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick</font
Where are you going?
I won't be long.
Bottoms up.
Meet me at the square!
Start anywhere you like.
Take your time, 007.
But in 5 minutes,
the head of the joint security service
is going to walk through that door
and I got to explain to him,
how one of our agents decided to porter off
to Mexico all on his own
and caused an international incident.
With all due respect, sir,
it could have been worse.
Worse?
You blew up half a bloody block.
Well, better half a block than
a whole stadium full of people.
You had no authority.
None.
As you know, we're in the
middle of the biggest
shake up in the history
of British intelligence.
The inks barely dry on this merger with MI5
and already they are itching for a chance
to scrap the 00 program forever.
And you just given them one.
You are right, sir.
You have got a tricky day ahead.
This is an official question.
Mexico city,
what were you doing there?
It's just a coincidence.
I was taking some overdue holiday.
Okay. Fine.
As of this morning,
you are officially grounded.
I'm standing you down
from all operations indefinitely.
Very good, sir.
Sir?
I don't know what you are
playing, but whatever it is
it has to stop...
now.
- So sorry, am I interrupting?
- Not remotely.
007, I'd like you to meet Max Denbigh,
head of the joint security service.
Well, it's a pleasure to finally meet
you, 007. I heard a lot about you.
- Most of it is good.
- Congratulations on your new appointment.
Thank you.
Suppose we should call you C, now.
- No, no. Max, please.
- No, I think I'll call you, C.
- C.
- As you wish.
Well, my door is always open, 007
for my employees.
This merger is going to be
a whole new chapter for us.
We're going to bring British intelligence
out of the dark ages into the light.
- That all sounds lovely.
- That will be all, 007.
Report to Q tomorrow
for medical, thank you.
Very good, sir.
James.
Moneypenny.
- So, how was the meeting?
- Very good, thank you.
Here, forensics finally released this.
What is it?
It's personal effects they
recovered from Sky-fall.
Perfect.
You can bring it to me later.
- What do you mean?
- My place, 9 o'clock.
- Evening.
- Come in.
Have you just moved in?
No.
Well, I like what you've
done with the place.
Your delivery.
Thank you.
- Would you like a drink?
- No, thanks. I'm not staying.
It's a shame.
What's going on, James?
There's not one person in MI6
who isn't talking about it.
Talking about what, exactly?
That what you did in Mexico
was one step too far.
That you're finished.
- What do you think?
- I think you're just getting started.
- I don't know what you mean.
- Fine
I think you've got a secret.
And it's something you won't tell anyone.
Because you don't trust anyone.
If anything happens to me for some reason.
I need you to you to do something.
Find a man called Marco Sciarra.
Kill him.
And don't miss the funeral.
- Jesus! Where did you get it?
- From my mailbox just after she died.
She was never short of surprises.
Wasn't gonna let death get
in the way of her job.
- I've been tracking Sciarra ever since.
- And what have you found?
Nothing significant, yet.
- When's the funeral?
- Three days. In Rome.
If you think M's signing off for that,
you're insane!
- He won't let you out of his sight.
- Yes, that's a bit of a problem.
Listen, could you do a little
quiet digging for me?
I heard a name in Mexico,
The Pale King.
You want me to be your mole!
Yes.
What makes you think you can trust me?
Instinct.
ORDER of TEMPORARY GUARDIANSHIP.
Poor old girl.
Rigged the demolition in a week.
Cheaper to knock her down, than
to rebuild.
Still, "Iron waits for no man"
and all that.
Anyway, all the money's been spent on this.
The New Center for National Security!
- So, that's C's new digs.
- You've met him, have you?
- Yesterday, what do we know about it?
- Perfect Whitehall Mandarin.
Wrote a dossier last year about how the
00 program was obsolete.
How drones could do our dirty work abroad.
- Went to school with our Home Secretary.
- Of course he did!
This murder's just the start of it.
Three days, there's a security
conference in Tokyo
to decide the New World Order.
If he gets his ways,
He'll have unlimited access to the
combined intelligence streams
of nine countries.
- Including us.
- Right.
Well, lots happened when you were away.
Train bombing in Hamburg
and an industrial explosion
in Tunisia.
Not great timing for us,
we're rather playing into C's hands.
M, well, let's say he's
feeling the pressure.
Yeah, I've noticed.
This way, 007. Be careful,
it's quite slippery.
Q wasn't exactly feeling at home in
Whitehall up with the new merger so,
He set up a shop here, away
from prying eyes as it were.
I hear he's get something rather
special planned for you.
I can hardly wait.
- Ah, 007.
- Q.
Please excuse the mess.
Lots of things were a
little bit up in the air
with the changes and all.
Couple of things to get through.
Shall we get started?
Just relax.
That's it, lovely.
- Now, you may feel a small...
- Christ!
Prick.
- What is it?
- Cutting edge nano technology.
Smart Blood.
Microchips in your bloodstream.
Allows us to track your movements
in the field.
You see those read-outs?
We can monitor your vital signs
from anywhere on the planet.
This is marvelous
I call it the Post-Mexico insurance
policy, by direct order then.
I completely understand.
Good.
Well I've just um... One last thing
and you could be on your way.
Magnificent isn't she?
0 to 60 in 3.2 seconds.
Fully bulletproof, few little
tricks up her sleeve.
Shame really, she was meant
for you but she...
been reassigned to 009.
But you can have this.
- Does it do anything?
- It tells the time.
Might cope with your punctuality issue.
- M's idea?
- Precisely.
Oh, one word of warning.
The alarm is rather loud.
If you know what I mean.
Like I do?
Oh, yes.
That odd thing is taking
quite a bit of time.
Mind you there wasn't much left to work on.
Only a steering wheel.
I believe I said "Bring it back in one
piece", not "Bring back one piece."
Anyway, enjoy your downtime, 007.
- Q.
- Yes?
Well now you know exactly where
I am, all the time.
Would you do something for me?
What do you have in mind exactly?
Make me disappear.
Um, may I remind you.
That I answer directly to M.
I also have a mortgage
and 2 cats to feed.
Oh.
Then I suggest you trust me.
Think of the cats.
Well it's lovely to see you, 007.
Lovely.
No, I'm meant to tell you.
The Smart Blood program is still
in its developmental phrase.
So, we may experience the odd drop
in coverage during the first 24 hours.
48 hours after administration.
After that it should work perfectly.
- I'll send you a postcard.
- Please don't.
Thank you J.
- Morning, what's that?
- Oh, just something from an admirer.
No, sir.
That was last week.
Morning, 009 has arrived to
pick up the DB10, sir.
- He's waiting upstairs.
- Oh, good. Yes. Fine.
Shit.
Sign of hope in the resurrection
I'm sorry for your loss.
- You knew my husband?
- Only briefly.
- What did you do?
- Life insurance.
- Probably too late for that.
- For your husband, yes.
- What about you?
- Me?
I hear the life expectancy of some
widows can be very short.
How can you talk like this?
Can't you see I'm grieving?
No.
- What a lovely view.
- You're wasting your time.
There are a hundred more
that would come after me.
All you buy me, is 5 minutes.
Excellent, time for a drink.
You killed him, didn't you?
- My husband.
- He was an assassin.
Trust me, he won't take it personally.
You signed my death warrant.
I was respected.
- Loyal to a man you hated.
- He trusted my silence.
With him gone, I'm a dead woman.
I can trust nobody.
I know the feeling well - Well, I
can tell you the victim tries to...
Then you have impeccable instincts - If
you don't leave now, we'll die together
I can think of worse ways to go.
Then you're obviously crazy, Mr...
Bond.
James Bond.
These people...
If you just knew what they could do.
The power they have.
Did you ever heard him mention
The Pale King?
No.
The organization.
They hardly ever meet.
But because what happened to my husband.
- They meet tonight.
- Why?
- To choose a replacement.
- Where?
La Pallazzo Cadenzza.
- At nine.
- Sounds like fun, I might drop by.
He was obsessed.
Spend more time with them
than with me.
Then, that man was a fool.
Leaving your number?
I'm calling an American
friend of mine, Felix.
I'll contact his embassy,
get you out of here.
You'll be safe.
Don't go, James.
If you go there, you're crossing over
to a place where there is no mercy
I have to go.
Good luck, Mrs. Lucia.
Hey, wait there.
Identify yourself, ass hole.
- Who are you?
- I'm Mickey Mouse, who are you?
Sorry.
Well, the latest figures
show that presently
control 70% of
antimalarial vaccines.
34% on HIV and 40% of all ontological
drug across Sub-Saharan Africa.
We've faced challenges from the
WHO and their campaign against
against out counterfeit pharmaceuticals.
We've faced
challenges from the WHO and
their campaign against
against out counterfeit
pharmaceuticals.
We have now identified the
key individuals to target.
We expect the same success as we had
against the Council of Union Traffic.
Dr. Vogel.
Don't let me interrupt you.
Now, onto the matter at hand.
After our successful attack in
Hamburg and Tunisia.
We abort an attack on Mexico City and
the death of our valued
colleague, Marco Sciarra.
Leave one of his duty, outstanding.
Señor Gerard, the Pale King
must be terminated.
Will you make the journey to Attersee?
Does anyone challenge Señor Guerra
for this position?
Welcome.
State your credentials
for succeeding, Señor Guerra.
It's funny.
All that excitement in Mexico City
rang a distant bell.
And now, suddenly this
evening it makes perfect sense.
Welcome, James.
It's been a long time.
But finally here we are!
What took you so long?
Cuckoo.
Ciao, Mickey Mouse!
Are you kidding me?
No!
What are you doing?
Moneypenny.
- Bond?
- Listen, Moneypenny.
Hamburg, Tunisia, Mexico City,
they're all linked.
It's one organization coordinating
multiple attacks.
- So she was right.
- Of course she was.
- I ran that check.
- Who is it?
My boss had his credit card stolen,
it's nothing.
- Why don't you go back to sleep?
- Don't be long.
- Who is that?
- No one.
- No, it was.
- It's just a friend.
At this time of night?
It's called life, James.
You should try it sometime.
The Pale King, it looks
like you've had dealings with him before.
- Quantum.
- Of course, Mr. White!
That's him.
Last unconfirmed sighting, Attersee
in Austria. Four months ago.
Hold that thought.
- You still there?
- Yeah.
- Run another name, will you?
- Okay.
A man called Franz Oberhauss.
Check his files, before and after
his death.
After his death? What
are you talking about?
Check his files, before
and after his death.
After his death?
What are you talking about?
Please, just do it.
Okay, Q. Give me something.
That's more like it.
Here goes nothing.
Good evening.
Do not let them tell you,
we need less surveillance.
We need more.
Much more.
I say again. _.
The 9 Eyes Committee will have
full access to the combined intelligence
streams of all member states.
More data, more analysis.
Less likelihood of terrorist attacks.
Ladies and gentlemen.
It's time for the security services
of the world to unite.
Alone, we are weak.
Together, we're a global power.
An unelected one.
Thank you.
We will now vote on the resolution.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please cast your votes.
The vote is 8 to 1 in favour.
However, as you know. We cannot proceed
unless the unanimous vote.
The 9 Eyes notion,
is therefore, not passed.
Democracy.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
This evening session is adjourned.
ARE WE SURE BOND'S IN LONDON?
- Yes, sir.
- Please tell me 007 is in London.
Oh, yes. Um.
I'll just take a look now, sir.
Because if he isn't, you're
in deep shit.
You've get precisely, 10 seconds.
I have him, sir.
He appears to be in Chelsea.
Well, I want eyes on him when
I get back. Understood?
I completely understand... Sir..
Do me a favour, make it quick.
Upstairs, Mr. White.
I always knew death would wear
a familiar face but not yours.
So to what do I owe this pleasure Mr. Bond?
I was at a meeting recently.
And your name came up.
I'm flattered London
is still talking about me.
It wasn't MI6. It was Rome.
Your team, not mine.
Last month, I found Thallium
in my cell phone.
It's done its job.
I have a few weeks. Maybe less.
So, here we are, Mr. Bond.
Two dead men
enjoying the evening.
- What did you do?
- I disobeyed them.
Followed him as far as I could and he...
changed.
Oh, I see. You grew conscious.
Our game is our game. But this...
women, children.
Well, the Thallium would suggest
he doesn't like you very much anymore.
I'm clear that the
feeling in mutual.
So, why don't you tell me how
to find him again?
- Oh, come on! Tell me where he is.
- He's everywhere!
Everywhere!
He's sitting at your desk,
he's kissing your
lover or he's eating
supper with your family!
You're protecting someone.
Your wife?
She left long ago.
Your son?
Your daughter.
You won't find her,
she's clever.
She's smarter than me,
she knows how to hide.
I can protect her,
if you tell me where he is.
- I can keep her alive.
- Yeah?
- You have my word.
- Your word?!
The word of an assassin?
That's my word.
American. You save her.
She can lead you to the
American, she knows the American.
Try the Chauffeur Clinic.
You're a kite dancing in a hurricane,
Mr. Bond.
So long!
Can't deny I'm impressed you got
HMG to cough up for all of us.
Good God, the government couldn't
afford this kind of facility.
No, it was benefactor.
Mostly from the private sector.
When it goes online,
this building will be
the most sophisticated
data gathering
system in history.
The World's digital ghost available
24/7
George Orwell's worst nightmare.
I'm glad you like it.
My commiseration on losing the 9 Eyes vote.
- Must have been a blow.
- Not really.
Only matter of time before South Africa
sees the light and you know what they say,
Rome wasn't built in a day,
a day and a half maybe.
Look, Max.
I know surveillance is fact of life.
It's how you use the information
that concerns me and who is using it.
This is what we need to do
to keep the people safe.
00 Program is prehistoric.
Come on, M. You can't tell me that one man
in the field can compete with all of this.
Running around out there
with his license to kill?
Have you ever had to kill a man, Max?
Have you?
To pull that trigger,
you have to be sure.
Yes, you investigate, analyze,
assess, target.
And then you have to look them
in the eye and you make the call.
And all the drones, bugs, cameras, transcripts,
all the surveillance in the world.
Can't tell you what to do next.
A license to kill.
Is also a license not to kill.
I didn't want to have to do this.
But it looks like
you still can't control your agents.
Bond, I ran that check.
Looks like you've had dealings
with him before, Quantum.
Of course, Mr. White!
Last unconfirmed sighting, Attersee
in Austria.
Run another name, will you?
So, something to be said
for total surveillance after all.
You watch MI6 agents?
I watch everyone.
Please take a seat.
I'll be with you in just a moment.
Monday, an assessment of
post-traumatic diagnostic was done.
Prescribed
medicine along with the TCC.
Please excuse me, Mr. Bond.
My name is Dr. Madeleine Swann.
Our job today's to analyze your needs
both physiological and physical.
Sounds pretty straight forward.
I hope you don't mind,
the video can be a bit distracting.
I haven't noticed.
I you've filled out
most of the paperwork.
Just a few questions to complete
your evaluation, if I may?
- You exercise?
- When I have to.
You consider employment to be
physiologically stressful?
Sometimes.
How much alcohol do you consume?
Too much.
SOME BROADER QUESTIONS: As a child, would
you say you were close to your parents?
My parents died when I was young.
Really? How old?
- Old enough to remember.
- How, if I may ask?
A climbing accident.
- Then who brought you up?
- Someone else.
Humor me.
How does one train at Oxford and
the Sorbonne
become a consultant, spend
2 years with medicine fortifier
and then end up here?
Forgive me, but anyone
might think you're hiding from something.
You're paying a lot of
money to be here, Mr. Bond.
- Who's asking the questions? You or me?
- Of course, carry on.
I see you left this final question blank.
What is your occupation?
Well, that's not the sort of thing
that looks good on a form.
- And why is that?
- I kill people.
Small world, huh?
- Where is he?
- Your father's dead, two days ago.
- How do you know?
- Because I was there.
- Did you kill him?
- I didn't have to.
He did it himself.
And you came all the way
just to tell me this?
That my father's dead?
I came to tell you that your life
is in danger and I need your help.
- Why?
- I made a deal with him to protect you.
You're lying.
Why would he trust you?
Because he knew that I needed
something in return.
- And what was that?
- To find the American.
- This interview's over.
- Dr. Swann.
You have 10 minutes to leave the building,
then I'm calling security.
Thank you, Dr. Swann.
- Can I get you something, sir?
- Vodka Martini, shaken not stirred.
I'm sorry, we don't serve alcohol.
I'm already starting to love this place.
Can I have the proactive
digestive enzyme shake?
Certainly.
If you've come for the car,
I parked it at the bottom of the toilet.
Oh, not to worry, 007.
It was only a 3 million pound prototype.
- Why are you here, Q?
- Oh, I just fancied a break to be honest
I've been a tad stressed at work
recently.
What we see is people crawling
all over us and the fact
everyone wants my balls for
Christmas decorations.
Get to the point - The point, 007,
is that Frank Oberhauser is dead.
Dead and buried.
And unless you don't
come back right now, my
career and Moneypenny's
will go the same way.
Do you understand? All hell is breaking
loose out there and here you a...
I saw him.
You thought you saw him.
We've been through the records.
Died in a avalanche, with
his father, 20 years...
Yes.
I know that but I saw him.
It's not someone I'd ever forget.
So, you have a lead?
- I have a name, American.
- Well, that narrows it down.
Look I'm sorry, 007, but time's up.
My whole career is on the line here.
Either you come back in and do this through
proper channels or I'll go directly to M.
Do one more thing for me,
then you're out.
Find out what you can from this.
- I really, really hate you right now.
- Thank you, Q.
- Monsieur? Now, please.
- Where are you staying?
At Desner, room 12 - One hour.
Here you are, sir.
One proactive digestive enzyme shake.
Do me a favour for me, will you?
Thrown that down the toilet.
Cut out the middle man.
No, stay!
What do you want?
What are you doing?
Can't any of you speak?!
Come on!
- Come out.
- Aargh, don't touch me!
Hey, you need to take a breath
and calm down.
- You're in shock.
- Get away from me! Just get away!
Did it cross your mind that you
lead them to me?!
I haven't got time for this.
You need to tell me everything you
know about American.
Go to hell!
I gave your father my word.
And why should I trust you?
Because my father did?
Because right now, Dr. Swann.
I'm your best chance of staying alive.
Dr. Swann, Q. Q, Dr. Swann.
- Hello.
- Enchanted.
- Bond, we need to talk. Alone.
- She knows.
- But Bond!
- What have you got?
- I owe you an apology, 007.
You are on to something.
Oberhauser is still alive,
the ring proves it.
And it seems they were all
part of one organization.
Le Chiffre, Quantum, Sciarra,
your friend, Mr. Silva.
And do you know who links them all?
- Him.
- Exactly.
This organization,
do you know what's it called?
S.P.E.C.T.R.E.
- Its name is SPECTRE.
- How does she know that?
Because my father was part of it.
And I think you ought to see this.
Looking at pictures from South Africa
right now, is what appears to be...
Q, go back to London.
M's gonna need your help.
Keep tracking me.
I will and Bond.
You have to find American.
He's our only link to Oberhauser.
It's not a person, it's a place.
Thank you.
This is where they spent the wedding night.
They came back every year.
Then they brought me with them too.
He kept coming back,
even after the divorce.
Well, then. I'm sorry.
What for?
What is it?
It's an inheritance.
- Want some?
- No, thank you.
You don't know what you're missing.
This can't be it.
Well, here's to your father.
I promised myself, I would never
be hurt by that man again.
I could have hold contact.
I didn't want to do anything
to do with him or his sick life.
And then with his dying
breath, he sends me you.
Ironic, no?
You shouldn't be so hard on him.
And now that I've just mentioned,
he would have been dead weeks ago.
The reason his heart was still
beating was you.
I mourn my father in my own
time, Mr. Bond.
And now, I'm going to bed.
Don't think for one moment,
this is where I fall into your arms.
Seeking solace for my dead daddy.
You sit there, keep watch.
That's what you're good at.
Come anywhere near me
and I will kill you.
I don't doubt it.
Look, there are 2 of you.
Two James. Lucky me.
Who sent you?
Who are you working for?
Now, where did you go?
Of course!
"VESPER LYND INTERROGATION"
What is it?
Nothing.
What's this?
Coordinates.
Your father was scanning for a particular
satellite, looking for someone.
He was looking for him.
And he sent me here to finish the job.
- I'm coming with you.
- No, you're not.
- I'd like you alive.
- I can look after myself.
That's beside the point.
- I might not be coming back.
- I know.
But I want to understand what
happened to my father.
So, where was he going?
Nowhere.
What's going on?
Well a meeting was brought forward,
did you not get the message?
No, we didn't.
- Shortest meeting I can remember.
- South Africa's on board I take it?
Yeah, well. Who can blame them?
9 Eyes is now officially sanctioned.
The new system goes live in
less than 72 hours.
It's a major step forward.
Global Intelligence Corporation
changes everythi...
As, you've said before.
Look, they've asked me to head
the new committee - Yes. And?
And I should tell you I've spoken
with the Home Secretary.
And in light of the new
information I have given him.
He's decided to close down the 00 Program
with immediate effect.
- You don't know what you're doing.
- It's not personal. It's the future.
And...
You're not - You're a cocky
little bastard, aren't you?
- I'll take that as a compliment.
- I wouldn't.
This isn't over yet.
- Will you press this for me?
- Thank you.
Pick it up.
I hate guns.
I promised him I'd protect you.
The first thing to do is to teach
you how to protect yourself.
- What if I shoot you be mistake?
- Wouldn't be the first time.
- Pick it up.
- I said I hate guns.
SIG-226, front side
rear side, hammer.
You just point it, squeeze the trigger
and try not to close your eyes.
Please, try it.
I don't have to teach you anything, do I?
A man once came to our
house to kill my father.
He didn't know I was upstairs
playing in my bedroom.
Papa kept a Beretta 9mm under
the sink with the bleach.
That's why I hate guns.
I think we'll skip
hand-to-hand combat.
Evening, sir.
Sorry to interrupt your supper.
- But we have some news.
- Evening, sir.
Using the Smart Blood, I've tracked
Bond to a point here. In North Africa.
The everyday map, registers it as an
empty desert - Exactly, but if you look
with a satellite blow up,
we can clearly see this.
We can't help him.
But, sir.
We know where he's heading.
C is watching everything we do.
We're only handing them more information.
- Sir, we can't just desert Bond.
- We have to, we only make him weaker.
- Sir, you know exactly where he is.
- Yes, I know,
If we can track him, so
can others.
Delete all the Smart Blood files,
everything.
He's on his own.
- You shouldn't stare.
- Well, you shouldn't look like that.
- May I get you a cup of tea?
- I'm not sure.
Gets me into trouble,
makes me do crazy things.
- Well, we can't have that.
- So, I'll have Vodka Martini, dirty.
Make that two.
- I have a question.
- What's that?
Why given any other possible option,
does a man choose a life
of a paid assassin?
Well, it was either that or a priesthood.
I'm serious.
Is this really what you want?
Living in the shadows?
Hunting, being hunted.
Always looking behind
you, always alone?
No, I'm not alone.
Answer the question.
I'm not sure I ever had a choice.
Anyway,
I don't stop to think about it.
What would happen if you did?
- Stop?
- Yes
I don't know.
- Your drinks, sir.
- Could you leave them there please?
You know, I think you're wrong.
I am?
We always have a choice.
I'll drink to that.
Shit!
What do we do now?
This might be a long way.
Are you having a second thought?
Too late now.
What's that?
That is a 1948
Rolls Royce Silver Wraith.
Please.
I'm scared, James.
Good afternoon, Mr. Bond. Dr. Swann
I want you to know just how
excited we all are to finally meet you.
Well, it's a pleasure to be here.
Your host invites you both to rest, relax
and meet him for drinks at 4:00.
- Tell our host, we won't be late.
- Wonderful!
Before we show you to
your rooms, just one more thing.
You be careful with that.
It's loaded.
Thank you.
This is a very special place.
He has requested,
you enter it alone.
Of course.
Champagne?
Maybe later.
Certainly.
I think we're meant to be impressed.
Touch it.
You can touch it if you want.
- Do you know what it is?
- It's a meteorite.
Yes, exactly!
Kartenhoff,
the oldest in human possession.
The very meteorite which made this crater.
Think about it.
So many years up
there alone, silent.
Building momentum until it
chose to make its mark on Earth.
Huge unstoppable force.
Except it did stop, didn't it?
Right here.
I can't tell you how much I have been
looking forward to this.
All of us here, together.
A reunion.
So glad you came too,
dear Madeleine.
You were just a girl,
when I saw you first.
I came to your home once
to see your father.
I don't remember that.
But I do.
Shall we?
What is this place?
Information.
Information is all.
Is it not?
For example..
You must know by now, that the 00 Program
is officially dead. For example..
You must know by now,
that the 00 Program is officially dead.
Which leaves me to speculate,
exactly why you came?
So, James. Why did you come?
I came here to kill you.
And I thought you came here to die.
- It's all the matter of perspective.
- Speaking of perspective,
- Is this live?
- Live and direct, 16:20 GMT.
What an uncanny coincidence.
The French have a saying:
"It's the fate of glass to break."
Well, maybe it's the fate of
spies to just disappear.
But with any luck,
we leave something behind.
In the meantime,
I'm sure C will keep you all busy.
Thank you all.
It's touching, don't you think?
Poor old James.
It looks like you're all alone.
Not much more than
a voyeur, are you?
Too scared to join in?
- I don't think you quite understand.
- I think I do. Too scared to join in?
- I think I do.
You set cities on fire, watch innocent
people burn so you can convince
governments to join the
intelligence network you paid for.
Not that complicated
I'm guessing out little friend, C,
is one of your disciples?
You could say that.
What does he get out of it?
Nothing?
- He's a visionary, like me.
- Visionaries, I see.
Psychiatry wards are full of them.
Where as you can see
what's right in front of you.
You came across me so many
times and yet you never saw me.
- Le Chiffre, Greene, Silva...
- All dead.
That's right.
A nice pattern developed,
you interfered
in my world, I destroyed yours.
Or did you think it was coincidence that
all the women in your life ended up dead?
Vesper Lynd, for example.
She was the big one,
has he told you about her?
An then of course,
your beloved M.
Gone forever.
Me...
It was all me, James.
It's always been me.
The author of all your pain.
You're a brave woman, my dear.
Now I understand why my
father lost his mind.
He didn't lose his mind,
he was just weak.
But at least he understood,
what he was up against.
You see, they fail to
comprehend a crucial fact that.
A terrible event,
can lead to something wonderful.
Since you mentioned
you father, I'll show you.
She's clever, she's smarter than me.
She knows how to hide.
And I'm going to protect her
if you tell me where he is.
- I can keep her alive.
- Yeah.
You have my word - I can keep her alive.
Yeah.
You have my word.
No, no, no, no, no.
Turn this off.
Word?
The word of an assassin?
Turn this off!
- This is important.
- I said turn it off!
I want you to understand something.
That's my word
Madeleine.
Look at me.
Look at him, Madeleine.
American.
You save her, she can lead you to
the American. She knows the American.
Try the Chauffeur Clinic.
You're a kite dancing in a
hurricane, Mr. Bond.
So long.
Things that bring people together.
Out of horror, beauty.
Torture is an easy and efficient way.
A man can watch himself
being disemboweled.
Surprise brings horror to the experience.
It can go over a distance,
it isn't taking
place where he is.
You know all too well, my dear Madeleine.
A man lives inside his head.
That's where the seed of the soul is.
James and I were both present recently.
When a man was deprived of his eyes.
And the most astonishing thing happened,
didn't you notice?
He wasn't there anymore.
He's gone even though, he's still alive.
This brief moment between life and death.
There was nobody inside his skull.
Most odd.
So, James.
I'm going to penetrate to where you are.
To the inside of you head.
The first probe will
play with your sight.
Your hearing and your balance.
- Just with a subtlest of manipulations.
- Well, get on with it then.
Nothing can be as painful
as listening to you talk.
Alright.
Let's begin!
Why are we doing this?
You probably know that, James here
lost his parents when he was young.
But did you know that it was my father who
helped him through this difficult time?
Over the course of 2 winters,
he taught him to ski, climb and hunt.
He soothed the wounds of the
poor little blue eyed orphan.
Asked me to treat him as a brother.
My little brother.
They formed quite an attachment.
No, you killed him.
Yes, I did.
You know what happens when a Cuckoo
hatches inside another bird's nest?
- It's forced to steal the eggs out.
- Yes.
Well, this Cuckoo made me
realize my father's life had to end.
In a way, he's responsible
for the path I took.
So, thank you. Cuckoo!
Do you know any bird calls, Franz?
Hello, pussy.
Franz Oberhauser
died 20 years ago, James.
In an avalanche,
alongside his father.
The man you're talking to now,
the man inside your head.
Is Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
- Fancy name?
- My mother's bloodline.
If the needle finds the correct spot
in the circumvoluþia spindle.
You'll recognize no one.
Of course, the faces of your women might
have changed a lot a lot, huh, James.
You won't know who she is.
Just another passing face
on your way to the grave.
He dies not knowing who you are.
The daughter of an assassin,
the only one who could have understand.
Shame.
I love you.
Do those blue eyes still recognize you?
I'd recognize you anywhere.
Watch.
One minute.
Did he say something?
I guess you did.
- What?
- Tempes... fugit...
I can't hear you, James.
I said, "doesn't time fly"?
There!
Let's go home.
It's not over yet.
- Nobody's ever heard of Hildebram.
- That is the general idea of safe houses.
- Exactly how safe is this, sir?
- We're about to find out.
It's safe. A bit of wait.
- I'm M.
- Madeleine Swann.
Pleased to meet you.
So, what do you have for me, 007?
The recently deceased head of SPECTRE,
Ernst Stavro Blofeld
and his chief of intelligence,
your new best friend, C.
Were about to take control of his very own
global surveillance system that he built.
- Right here, under our noses.
- Then we'd better move.
The system goes online at midnight.
If that happens SPECTRE
will have control of everything.
So, you and I will have a
quiet word with C. While Q
hacks into the system and
stops it getting online.
- It won't be easy.
- He'll find a way.
He always does.
- It's good to have you back 007
- Sir.
- James, I can't.
- I'll come back for you.
- When it's all over.
- I know I can't.
- You can't stay here or...?
- I can't go back to this life.
And I'm not doing to ask you to change.
This is who you are.
- You're saying goodbye.
- Yes.
Take care.
You're a good man, James.
Are you in yet, Q?
Few layers of impenetrable
layers to go but I think
I'm getting somewhere.
- They've seen us.
- Move back!
Go!
Get into the building!
Move. Move!
Go back and find M, now!
We need them both.
Not a good feeling
being watched, is it?
Don't tell me you're
responsible for this.
No, but my quartermaster is.
And he's extremely talented.
Bravo, but in case you haven't
realized it. You two are out of a job.
So you're trespassing - I'm afraid you've
got the wrong end of the stick, Max.
We're going to stop this
system going online.
- Then I'm going to bring you in.
- On what grounds exactly?
Poor taste in friends.
Take a look at the world.
Chaos!
Because people like you.
Paper-pushers, politician are too spineless
to deal which what needs to be done.
So, I made an alliance to put
the power where it should be.
And now you want to throw it
away for the sake of democracy.
Whatever the hell that is.
How predictably moronic.
But then isn't that
what M stands for?
Moron?
Now you know what C stands for.
Careless.
Come on!
No, no, no!
You're a hard man to kill, Blofeld.
I do hope that
doesn't hurt too much.
Oh, my wounds will heal.
What about yours?
Look around, James. Look!
This is what's left of your world.
Everything you ever stood for,
everything you believed in. A ruin.
Why am I here?
- Did you miss me?
- No.
But I know someone who does!
- Where is she?
- That's for you to find out.
Three minutes, this
building will be demolished.
Well, I can get out easily.
But you have a choice.
Die trying to save her, or.
Save yourself and
live with the pain.
You're bluffing.
Am I?
I've really got you
now haven't I?
Oh, that's rather sweet.
They always know which button to press.
Madeleine!
Come on, come on.
Yes!
Let's go. After you.
Why can't you just face it, M?
- You don't matter anymore.
- Maybe I don't.
But something has to.
- Dead.
- Any word on Bond?
No, but I can hazard a guess.
Madeleine!
- Do you trust me?
- Do I have a choice?
Not anymore.
Come on!
Goodbye, James Bond.
- Sir, there's a terrorist alert.
- Mallory, 00 Section.
Stand them down.
The Go Team hold. Stand down.
Finish it.
Finish it!
Out of bullets.
And besides,
I've got something better to do.
Under the special
measures act of 2001
I'm detaining you on behalf of
Her Majesty's government.
Bond?
- What are you doing here?
- Good morning, Q.
- I thought you'd gone.
- I have.
There's just one thing I need.
Hope it helped -> bozxphd