Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Morning!
Good morning!
-Coffee?
-Okay.
Yes?
Good morning.
My name is Marta.
I'm a supervisor at your bank.
-Yes?
-You've missed 6 payments.
Your outstanding debt
is over 120 thousand euros
In accordance with the penaIty
-contract condition number 26...
-Wait, Miss.
What contract?
The one you signed, sir.
I aIready toId you, I'm broke!
No savings, nothing!
Yes, sir, but we're tired
of hearing the same oId excuses.
We've been forced to put you on
an internationaI
bIack Iist of fraudsters.
Hey, I'm no mafioso.
I'm a simpIe truck driver.
Worse! I'm a sIave.
It's your fauIt I Iost my trucks,
you bastards. I Iost my wife,
my home, my kids, everything.
You know what?
Stick the debt up your arse!
Did you hear me?
Sir, we're concerned about
the mentaI heaIth
-of our clients.
-What?
We can offer you
psychoIogicaI heIp
at a 30% discount.
PsychoIogicaI heIp?
What the fuck
are you taIking about?
You sound tense, sir.
Are your veins throbbing?
What did you say?
Are you getting nervous?
Hear strange voices in your head?
Like your niece's?
Artichoke! How are you, sweetheart?
Bastard!
It's AIma!
AIma! AIma!
You bastard!
You got me there!
Dance, Arti, dance!
You and that other wanker laughing.
She tricked me!
AIma.
We can't find him anywhere.
We've caIIed everyone
and Iooked everywhere.
Nobody's seen him.
THE OLIVE TREE
You hear that?
Grandad.
Grandad, Iisten.
ls that a nightingale singing?
No, it's a greenfinch.
They say the Romans
might have pIanted these.
Who knows.
This tree is at Ieast
two thousand years oId.
You know how Iong that is?
I don't.
I know it's a Iong time.
It's been here my whoIe Iife
and hasn't changed.
This is where the new tree sprouts from.
I'II show you, then you do it.
String...
And who taught you
how to graft?
Tighter, tighter.
My grandad taught my dad
and my dad taught me
and I'm teaching you.
That's how Iife works.
You pass it down.
A new tree!
Let's hope it grows
Iike this one.
Look, Grandad! A monster.
You see it?
Where?
Here's an eye,
the other eye, the nose,
and the mouth is super wide open.
But it has no teeth.
You see it?
We'II keep the monster company.
And we'II bring him grub to eat.
It's not here, Grandad.
It's not here.
Come on, Iet's go.
Come on.
He's got us right where he wants us.
Running after him,
as usuaI,
at his service.
Worried sick, chasing him around...
Give me a break.
He just wants attention.
Just Iike you with that hair.
-Luis...
-Leave her aIone.
He has us aII on edge.
Like he wants us to suffer.
What? You disagree?
Something to say?
Great.
SiIence.
I know that punishment
aII too weII.
Rafa.
Don't Iook at her.
Where are you going?
I fucking caIIed you six times,
you moron!
My battery ran out! I'm sorry.
Change of pIan, you have to take
the chickens to VaIencia.
Dickhead! I had to come
aII the way out here to teII you!
I'm sorry.
-Fuck!
-AIma...
Leave him aIone, you arsehoIe!
Crazy fucking bitch!
I'm going to smash your face,
you arsehoIe!
You don't have the baIIs.
Bring it on.
-Came on then! Try it!
-Fuck, Rafa!
Get back in the car!
-What are you doing, AIma?
-Get out of here!
Just you wait, you crazy bitch!
Running off?
I'm standing right here.
You're a fucking nutter!
Anytime, champion!
You're crazy!
He couId have reaIIy hurt you!
I don't give a shit.
Rafa.
You're not going to ask me
out tonight?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Ask me.
Ask me out, Rafa.
You know what the nurse said,
Grandad?
That the Iast thing you forget
are songs.
ShouId we try it?
Let's try a song.
How shouId I put my Iips?
Like this?
Yes.
No!
It tickIes.
I'm more scared of you than the dentist!
What are you doing here?
Get off my Iand!
-Dad, we onIy came to...
-Shut up! I know why you're here.
Get off my Iand!
And don't come back
or I'II shoot you!
-Leave! Out!
-Take it easy.
Out!
You too, out!
30 thousand euros, Dad.
5 miIIion pesetas!
You've worked Iike a sIave
your whoIe Iife
and what have you got?
There's cheap mixed oiI
everywhere.
Nobody gives a shit
about your precious oIive oiI!
CaIm down.
It's the truth!
Nobody cares about our work!
Some of your friends have soId
their oIdest trees
for firewood.
We've worked our asses off
our whoIe Iives in those fieIds
and you've never paid us
a penny.
You owe it to us.
What do you think?
I think that I'm not going to seII.
That tree is not ours.
Damn it...
It was passed down
from grandparents to parents
and from parents to chiIdren.
If I seII that oIive tree
and give you the money,
next week you won't have the tree,
the money or the restaurant.
You just ignore us!
That oIive tree has no price.
It's sacred.
That tree is my Iife and you want
to take my Iife away.
It's onIy a tree!
And we're your chiIdren!
It'II be yours, I can't take it with me!
You're stuck in the past
and you're sinking us aII!
That tree isn't even ours.
It beIongs to Iife, to history.
Don't give me that history buIIshit!
We have famiIies to feed!
Grandad!
There's a IittIe girI!
Stop, stop, stop!
Be carefuI!
The girI is up there!
Stop the machine!
-Get down!
-Stop the machine, cut the engine!
Stop!
Listen to your mother.
AIma, come down, damn it!
-Come down!
-AIma!
Come down.
Come down!
Get her down, Luis!
AIma, come down from there!
Come on.
-Come down!
-Come on, get down.
CIimb down, damn it!
-Come on, cIimb down.
-AIma!
Come down!
AIma, come here, darIing.
Don't cry.
The monster...
His weight Ioss and deterioration
are very aIarming.
If we can check him into the hospitaI
for a few days, we can run some tests,
stimuIate his appetite
and maybe start thinking about
a home with fuII time care.
If it's for the best.
I try to spend as much time
as I can here, but...
it's not enough.
Luis can't do everything himseIf
and aIso watch Dad.
We'II aII be Iess worried.
You're going to kiII him.
If he doesn't eat, he'II die.
Your grandfather isn't
your grandfather anymore.
Grandpa is gone, AIma.
There's nothing wrong with him.
Nothing.
You're teIIing a doctor
how to do her job?
What do you mean, sweetheart?
He's in mourning, that's aII.
Grandma died a Iong time ago.
Not the fucking tree again!
What are you trying to do,
screw up the whoIe famiIy?
It's Iike a Iost chiId, isn't it?
The worst part is not knowing.
What if it's in a beautifuI pIace
somewhere?
Eh?
With water,
with peopIe who take care of it...
It wouId be a happy monster, eh?
If you knew
wouId you be more at peace?
Grandad, do you want to die?
Is that it?
Do you want to die?
Grandad!
Grandad, I heard you.
I heard you.
Did you sing?
Listen.
Let the wind blow...
Did you hear that?
I think it was onIy
a deep breath.
No, pIease, I heard you.
Sing with me.
Let the wind blow,
let it blow hard...
PIease, Grandad.
PIease, pIease.
I know you're there.
I know it.
It took me and your dad
a whoIe day to put those there.
God!
How did we swaIIow aII that shit?
For what?
-I Iost EstreIIa...
-He Ieft Mum...
No, that's not how it was.
Okay, she Ieft him. Because
he never took care of her.
No wonder she feII apart
and Ieft him.
We worked Iike donkeys.
We aII made mistakes.
And he took care of her,
in his own way.
And how did he treat Grandad?
Have you ever wondered
how Grandad treated him?
Have you?
Because with us he was a very tough
oId man.
We used to say he cared about
his trees more than us.
With you he might have been marveIIous,
not with us.
Okay, Arti, Ieave it!
You know how humiIiating
it must be for your dad
to move back to the famiIy house?
To the same bedroom as a boy?
Put yourseIf in his shoes.
Jesus Christ.
You never give up!
One thing I've never understood, Arti.
At that time,
banks were Ioaning money
to anybody, right?
They say anybody
couId get credit. Okay?
Then why did you need
the 30 thousand for the tree?
It's what the mayor
asked for...
to buiId so cIose to the beach.
Disgusting!
You're aII the fucking same.
No, we're not, AIma!
We did it for you and your cousins.
So we couId have a famiIy
business.
Not our choice to bribe the mayor,
that's how things were done.
Sorry we're not aII fucking saints.
We'II see what you do
for your kids.
Look how happy he was.
Look at EmiIio.
What ever became of him?
I stiII remember the drinks
he used to mix.
You know what I remember?
His chubby fingers and bitten naiIs.
That's what.
He used to stick them down my pants
when I was waitressing here.
I tried to teII Dad aII summer.
The whoIe summer.
I was so ashamed
that I couIdn't...
One night I toId him.
In the kitchen.
Know what your brother said?
Nothing.
He didn't say a word.
And he waIked out.
AIma, he must have been...
He must have froze.
He didn't know what to do.
Go to heII.
You and your brother can both
go to fucking heII.
He didn't know what to do?
It's very easy!
Protect your daughter,
arsehoIe!
I have no idea.
Some went aII the way to China,
the MiddIe East, aII over Europe,
even the Vatican.
Thousands of them.
Over a hundred
went to one bank in Madrid.
Yeah, but I have the saIe date.
I onIy want to know
where it is, who bought it...
Who do you think I am,
InterpoI?
Go on, get out of here.
We're not serving hippies today.
Do you remember me?
I was in the tree, I cIimbed up
whiIe you were uprooting it.
You were shouting at me.
I was onIy 8 years oId.
Just get the fuck out of here.
Your famiIy made 30 thousand euros.
Consider yourseIves Iucky.
You know what?
I'd start Iooking for your tree in China!
Beat it.
I remember everything.
EspeciaIIy that pig-face
of yours.
Go on, piss off!
Your name is AIma, isn't it?
Yeah.
I was there that day.
I was in the car.
I went with my brother.
Yes, he's my brother.
I'II never forget it.
Your grandfather's tree
was very speciaI,
but many die within the first 15 years
of transpIant,
so you might never find it.
But this couId heIp.
That's it, isn't it?
Yes.
Thank you.
DusseIdorf, Germany.
Wow!
It's a huge company.
There it is!
It's in the middIe of the Iobby,
Pride of pIace!
-It's a star.
-What's the date?
The website is up to date,
must stiII be there.
HoIy shit! They're using it
as the company Iogo!
Your grandfather wiII be
super proud.
It wiII kiII him.
Fucking Iocked up, no fresh air!
AIma, it's not a tiger,
doesn't need to run around.
It Iooks super cooI, in one of the most
important countries in the worId.
It'II break his heart.
That's Adri. I'm going, okay?
See you Iater.
Ok, Photoshop, I can put it
where you want.
How about outside in a garden?
LittIe white Iie so he doesn't suffer
and he'II never know.
That's the probIem, he knows.
How couId he know?
He can't even taIk.
Wiki, he knows and I'm not
going to Iie to him.
Okay, fine.
Then what do we do?
Grandpa.
I know where it is.
I don't know how,
but I'm going to bring it back.
I'II bring it back, I promise.
HoId on, Grandad.
HoId on, pIease,
I'II bring it back for you.
Mr. Gorbicht was German,
retired, very rich, who moved
to VaIencia. And very reIigious.
And since the oIive tree
is sacred in the BibIe,
he had a dream to donate
an ancient tree to his church.
From the time of Christ.
And which tree did he pick?
My grandad's.
Mr. Gorbicht died 4 years ago
I got this Ietter from
the minister at his church,
the San Lucas Church
in DusseIdorf, Germany.
Here's what he says:
Quiet everybody.
She's taIking about Ramón.
''I've spoken with my parishioners.
When we accepted Mr. Gorbicht's donation,
our intentions were weII meant,
but a mistake.
Many young members
of our community
are aware of the sacredness of nature,
and the environment,
so after much prayer,
we have made a decision.
We wouId Iike
this sacred tree to bring peace
and harmony to your famiIy,
especiaIIy to the eIderIy gentIeman
who has cared for it his entire Iife.
CIearIy, it shouId be returned to
the spot where it was pIanted and grew.''
They're giving it back!
He speaks great Spanish.
Yeah... He was a missionary
in GuatemaIa for 25 years.
-You taIked to him?
-Yeah.
And where is the tree?
In DusseIdorf.
In the church gardens,
by the River Rhine.
How did you find it?
The garden centre toId me.
Shit! And here's me thinking the Germans
were a bunch of greedy fuckers
who came down here
in their oId age to get their piIes
sorted on our heaIth system!
I apoIogize!
Now aII we need is one truck
with a crane and two drivers.
To DusseIdorf?
Cost a fortune!
It's way, way up there, AIma.
Lots of countries in between.
It's 1,659 kiIometres.
That's not so far.
We can take advantage of
the hoIiday weekend coming up.
What do you mean, ''we''?
-If you borrow your boss' truck...
-What?
You can take turns driving
and be back before he notices.
Borrow a 250,000 euro truck
from the psychopath
you just peIted with eggs?
NeIson wiII cut your baIIs off.
Hey...
No.
-And it's my wedding anniversary!
-But you're divorced!
But we stiII Iove each other.
If EstreIIa finds out I went
to DusseIdorf for a tree...
No way.
DieseI, insurance, toIIs...
AII that expense.
Ijust soId my motorcycIe
for 1,000 euros.
Right.
That's not enough.
What about the permits?
You don't need permits.
Open borders.
Grandad's dying!
He can't even remember
his own chiIdren!
He'II remember the tree, damn it!
AIma, you're too upset.
Too emotionaI.
Let's think it over. We're taIking about
a 14 ton Ioad!
If I have to waIk aII the way there
and drag it back myseIf, I wiII.
You can both go fuck yourseIves!
AIma!
-Wait!
-Don't touch me!
We'II taIk it over, AIma!
She's mad as a hatter.
I soId an oIive tree too.
Fuss about nothing.
Try it, whet your appetite.
Come on, Dad.
They never stop eating!
From chick to chicken in 40 days.
I'm going to puke!
I'm a vegetarian, AIma.
Asking you to feed them,
not eat them.
It's easy, AdeIIe.
Press a few buttons, that's it.
I wrote it aII down for you.
Here, take it.
What if they expIode?
HardIy ever happens.
This one's dead.
Get that thing away from me!
-They have to be picked up.
-Disgusting!
It touched me!
Disgusting!
I contacted a website
for Spaniards abroad
and spoke to SoIe,
a Spanish girI in DusseIdorf.
She'II caII you Iater on Skype.
You're a genius, Wiki, thanks.
What about the energy company?
I've sent emaiIs to the CEO and
the head of each department, but nothing.
I've caIIed 40 times.
They just Iaugh and hang up.
I don't think you'II get
anywhere near the tree.
Phew.
AIma.
Stay a few days Ionger
and we'II think this through.
I can't, Grandad's worse.
Going without a pIan
is stupid.
Then keep thinking.
Wiki, you've got the brains
I've got the brass neck.
And you've got the chickens.
-You're crazy.
-You shouId be Iocked up.
Fine, I know!
None of this makes any sense,
I can see that.
But sometimes you just have
to dive in.
Headfirst.
You begin the journey...
and peopIe wiII heIp you
aIong the way.
Why shouId they heIp you?
-Here, take it.
-No, no.
-Yes.
-From both of us,
just in case.
I'II be fine, okay?
Nothing wiII happen to me.
HoIy shit! Look at them.
Like Iambs to the sIaughter.
Not a cIue of the mess
you've got them into.
You have to teII them.
They'II go crazy.
No, not a word.
If I teII them now,
they'II be off, back home.
Just think of something
and skype me Iater.
WeII, what do you think?
What do I think?
What kept you? That's what I think.
I'II be damned.
Ricardo, Iisten to me.
He went to Madrid
with his girIfriend.
He won't be back for 3 days.
l was wrong.
l want the truck back now.
We're on the road!
CaIm down.
I'II keep you posted,
I promise.
-Where did you say?
-Granada. It'II be fine.
Got a bad feeIing
about this.
Don't worry, it'II be fine.
Trust me.
Okay, taIk to you Iater.
Bye.
That was the security guard
at the garage. Shitting himseIf.
But he's a good Iad.
He wanted to heIp me out.
About this German minister.
You have got his address?
Any more stupid questions?
Don't shit me, AIma.
It's a Iong, Iong way.
What if he changes his mind?
Come on!
He's a minister, protestant, German.
Can you imagine anyone more serious?
Okay, then.
Granada, land of my dreams...
Granada he says, what a dick!
I'II be damned!
Hi, l'm Sole.
This is Katrine,
a law student.
This is Marine.
-Hi.
-This is Sophie.
She's a social media manager and
likes getting into trouble sometimes.
Have you heard back from
the energy company yet?
No, my friends have tried caIIing
but they're brushing us off.
She hasn't heard back.
They think it's a joke.
No wonder.
l wrote to the CEO of the company
and offered to pay them back
for the tree,
like a loan, with interest,
but...
She offered to buy the tree
and pay in instaIIments.
How naive!
It's embarrassing.
Coming aII the way from Spain
without a pIan!
The tree is in their headquarters.
It's their fucking Iogo!
They paid 30,000 for it.
ls she crazy or what?
She says I'm crazy, right?
lt's a bit too much, Alma.
Do you really think you can
come and pick up the tree,
just like that?
That's the probIem,
the guys with me do.
What do you mean?
l told them a lie.
l told them the tree is at a church
and they're giving it back.
No fucking way!
The guys with her don't know.
This girI is fucking brainIess.
You can count me out.
Forget it.
Look, l know it's crazy.
But l couldn't just sit there
and watch my grandfather
die of heartbreak.
Do you understand?
l couldn't.
Wiki sent us photos.
l'm sorry about your grandfather.
Can you please help me?
I didn't know.
I didn't see it coming.
I had six huge trucks
Iike this one
worth two miIIion.
I was owed a fortune.
One day I was somebody,
the next a nobody.
It aII vanished, Iike that.
No warning.
You must have known.
No, sweetheart.
They Iied to me.
I Iied to myseIf.
I Iied to EstreIIa.
The Iies got bigger and bigger.
More Iies and more Iies.
I couIdn't stop Iying.
One day, EstreIIa
totaIIy smashed up the kitchen.
The whoIe country
is Iying to itseIf.
That's what she said.
And she Ieft me.
So I decided to change my Iife.
I promised. I swore on our son's Iife
that I wouId never Iie to her again.
That I wouId aIways teII the truth.
And yesterday I went to her house
and said:
''Look, EstreIIa. I'm going
to miss our anniversary
because I'm going to DusseIdorf.
WeII done, Arti.
You toId her the truth.
She burst out crying.
She thought I was getting paid.
Did you expIain to her?
My Iips stuck fast, Rafa.
GIued shut.
You moron! She's going
to find out when you get back.
I'm such a fucking idiot!
Disgusted with myseIf.
I couId have toId her.
I couId have said: ''Look, EstreIIa.
I'm picking up the tree in DusseIdorf,
I'II be back two days.
She'd have caIIed me a dunce
but she'd have understood.
But in the moment
I fucking Iied to her again!
Why can't we just trust each other?
Look each other in the eye,
put the cards on the deck?
Be honest with each other?
Work it out together?
Am I right, darIing?
Arti...
Son of a bitch...!
What are you doing?
There's a wanker Iives up here
who owes me 90 grand.
Answer, you fucker.
Answer.
I know you're there.
Come out, you bastard!
I know you're in there!
Show your face,
you piece of shit!
Arti.
We're wasting time.
No, no. I bet the motherfucker
is spying on us
with a teIescope from a bunker,
the bastard.
StiII has the fancy car.
He says it's his brother-in-Iaw's.
And the house his mother-in-Iaw's.
You Iying piece of shit!
Bastard!
And this?
What about this? He bought it
for his idiot girIfriend.
Because she Ioved shopping
in New York.
That's what things were Iike
in those days.
Weekend shopping in New York!
CaIm down and Iet's go.
My sweaty 18 hours a day
working my arse off
so he couId buy this big Iump of junk!
He stiII owes me 90 grand.
90 grand!
I'II show the motherfucker.
Where are you going?
What I'm saying, you moron,
is that Germans
-Iove American stuff.
-Do you understand your idiot uncIe?
We'II seII the statue
for a fortune there.
What are you taIking about?
Like aII those gnomes they buy
for their front gardens.
TeII Wiki to find a rich German
and we'II seII it on the Internet.
Okay.
Hey, maybe we can
pass by DisneyIand in Paris
and pick up a Mickey Mouse?
Two thousand years!
He reminds me of my grandfather.
Look at that.
It's not just a ''thing'' to him.
It's sacred.
Something isn't right here.
What isn't right?
CentraI Heating or a hot shower?
What wouId we do without them?
What do you make of her?
It aII sounds a bit daft,
but she gets me.
She's a Iiar.
She tricked her friends to come
to Germany for something that's not theirs.
But she has a point!
I couId open a page on Facebook.
WouIdn't take Iong.
See what happens.
It's a good story.
Some peopIe make things happen.
Yeah, right. The worId is fuII
of irritating cIowns.
Katrin!
FRANCE
See who it is.
Your brother.
Your father.
And he aIways wiII be, AIma.
When I first toId him,
he couIdn't beIieve it.
You know what he said?
How brave you were.
More than I can say for him.
He's onIy trying to heIp.
It's his way of saying sorry.
That's not so terribIe, is it?
AIma.
Take it easy.
Open cast mining,
chopping down forests, moving viIIages...
''SustainabiIity.''
And their Iogo is a tree...
What hypocrites!
How's the Facebook page going?
More interest than I expected.
There is an activist group
against the tree feIIing of the company.
They're passing on our page.
Others just think she's crazy.
Lots of people angry with
RRR's hypocrisy.
We can organize something.
l need photos of the trip for FB.
You keep your mouth shut.
I reaIIy Iike that.
Not asking questions
the whoIe time.
Good just to be in siIence.
WeII, you don't Iisten much.
I don't take it personaI anymore.
You've got too much
going on up there.
Stop.
Shit, Rafa.
I'm sorry, I can't.
But you can with a stranger.
Alma, this is getting crazy.
A local paper saw
the Facebook page.
They want to talk to you.
Can l give them your number?
And your dad is driving me crazy.
He came to talk to me.
-What am I going to do?
-l don't know.
This is exactly what l said
right before you left.
What did the guys say?
Alma...
Fuck!
You haven't told them!
Rafa's risking his job!
Show him a little respect
and tell him, shit!
Rafa's taIking to his boss.
He had a fight with his girIfriend
and he came back.
He says he wants his truck.
Come on, we have to make
a decision.
l'm going to rip your head off!
Do you realize what you've done?
You're going to ruin me!
Answer me, you fucking clown!
One more insuIt
and I'II hang up on you.
Where the fuck are you?
Shut up!
And mind your manners.
I'm going to DusseIdorf.
What did you say?
You mean Dusseldorf, in Germany?
Fucking hell!
Listen, this is aII my fauIt.
I Iied to Ricardo.
If you fire him, I'II seII your truck
to the Russian mafia.
Rafa, cooI it.
What the hell...?
l'm going to cut your balls off!
-I'II teII you something, NeIson.
-Rafa, don't...
You're a buIIy, an arsehoIe
and you can go fuck yourseIf!
You just Iost your job, shit.
I don't care!
I'II find something eIse.
Maybe I'II stay in DusseIdorf.
No. I want you both to go back.
Let me taIk to him.
I'II say this was aII a mistake
and that I Iied to you guys.
Let me taIk to him. I'II apoIogize,
return the truck and he'II forgive you.
I can't bear it.
Give me your phone.
-Give it to me.
-No.
Give me your fucking phone!
-Give it to me!
-That's enough! Fuck!
As usuaI, you've forgotten
one detaiI.
This isn't just about you anymore.
We have a say in this too.
Don't be an idiot.
Give me the phone.
No, AIma.
I'II be waiting in the truck.
I'm not going back
without the tree, AIma.
You don't understand.
This is a disaster.
Not after aII this.
PIease. PIease.
Arti, you don't understand.
Come on, Iet's go.
No, everything okay.
Have you ever feIt Iike
you were going to burst?
And compIeteIy crack up?
It happened to me once.
When I was 18.
When I was training
with VaIencia FootbaII CIub.
I thought I was going to make it,
but one fiIthy tackIe
screwed my career.
I wanted to smash the guy's head.
I wanted to kiII him.
I wasted two years of my Iife
in a rage.
Augustin, my physio...
knew what I was going through
just from his hands.
And one day, after a session,
I broke down.
I burst out crying,
Iike a IittIe boy.
And he Iooked at me and said:
''Do you want to get better?
Then don't add to your own
misfortune.''
And suddenIy I understood.
Look, AIma.
You can spend your whoIe Iife
picking at the same oId wound,
feeding the pain,
no chance to heaI.
But sometimes it's better
to Iet things go.
Move on.
Nourish what you have,
not what's gone.
You think I add to my own
misfortune?
We aII do.
Some more, some Iess.
GERMANY
You haven't sIept?
Germany.
Even the name makes me feeI shorter
than I am.
I know I'm not very smart,
but I feeI twice as dumb here.
They're aII so taII...
And they speak great EngIish.
Must be something they put
in the sausages.
Have you got the address
of the church?
An activist group has been
denouncing RRR for a long time.
They loved your story.
Their logo stinks!
Tell me when you get there.
-Think someone might steaI it?
-No.
It couId be a big hit
right here next to the Rhine.
With boats passing by, Iike New York.
-Yeah, right.
-Sure.
Thought we're going to a church?
First we have to sign papers
in an office.
HoIy shit!
That's our tree.
What the fuck is it doing here?
Where's the minister?
Are we meeting him here?
No.
What?
You mean...
there's no minister?
No minister, no church,
no HoIy WiIIie who died in VaIencia
and we're not getting the tree back?
Is that it?
Sometimes your Iips stick fast.
You said so yourseIf.
Okay, back home, Rafa.
Your Iips stick fast.
But not in fucking DusseIdorf!
What the heII are we doing here?
WeII, AIma?
What are we doing here?
What are we doing?
Somebody expIain to me
what we're doing here.
-Let's go.
-What are we doing here?
-Can't you see she's in shock?
-She's in shock?
I'm in fucking shock!
-What are we doing here?
-Let's go.
Don't fuck with me!
Get your hands off, pIease.
Hands off.
Do we have permission
to take the tree or not? TeII me.
Are you teIIing me
we drove up over 1,500 kiIometres
in a forty-ton truck
to pick up this giant tree
without permission?
Hey!
Okay, okay...
This tree beIongs to my famiIy!
This tree is ours!
Get your fucking hands off me!
I'm Ieaving!
I'm Ieaving on my own!
Let me go!
That's enough!
This is our tree!
Let me go!
Get off me.
AIma.
AIma, teII me what
we're fucking doing here.
Leave her aIone.
What the fuck is going on here?
Let's hear it.
You didn't know, right?
I had a feeIing.
AfeeIing?
You're joking me.
What? I guessed but I wasn't sure.
Since when?
From the very start.
So I'm the onIy dickhead once again.
Driving up here Iike a happy donkey
you two Iaughing
at the dunce?
Why didn't you say anything?
Why didn't you?
Why didn't you teII me
to piss off?
Why didn't you?
I was going to hitchhike, Rafa! Why?
Fuck!
How can you be so stupid?
How? You Iost your job!
For what? TeII me!
Why?
Look at me, shit!
I hate you. I hate you.
And I hate you too.
You can both go fuck yourseIves.
Piss off back home
in your stupid truck!
I tried to teII you!
Don't you see? I tried, shit!
I tried to teII you in the cafeteria.
What a pair of dickheads!
Dickheads!
Let me get this straight.
It's our fauIt?
It appears so.
You must reaIIy Iike her.
I feeI so...
deceived, AIma. So betrayed.
I'm so sick of everyone treating me
Iike a prick.
But that's what I am,
a prick.
For trusting you.
I've aIways Ioved you to bits,
since you were this high.
And you couIdn't trust me?
Look at me.
Me!
What was the pIan?
I've never feIt so insignificant
in my whoIe Iife.
Never.
I'm going back to the truck.
Then I'm going home,
with or without you both.
I'm a stupid dickhead!
Stupid statue!
Stupid Iife!
Dickhead!
Where is she?
She says she won't move untiI
she taIks to the owner of the tree.
Who does she fucking think she is,
Mahatma Gandhi?
You're serious?
What a famiIy.
What a bIoody famiIy!
Fine, I'm Ieaving.
It's over.
I'm getting in that truck and
going home, with or without you both.
You got that?
That's what she said.
That you and I shouId go home.
Fine, that settIes it.
Let's go.
Come on.
What a girI.
What a bIoody girI!
I'm sorry.
I'm reaIIy sorry.
Look.
Thanks for your support, Sole.
We're camping outside the building
until they talk to us.
AIma...
Dad.
Thanks for teIIing me.
How is Grandad?
PIease, don't stop taIking to him.
Don't stop.
Okay.
Their spokesperson contacted me.
Said there's nothing to talk about.
They won't see you.
l'm not leaving
until l talk to them.
lf they won't talk,
they'll have to listen.
Luis!
Can you hear me?
What?
Okay.
Good thing we brought the truck.
I'm sorry, Grandad.
I'm sorry.
I did everything I couId,
I reaIIy did.
Look.
It's from our tree.
I found it.
And we're going to repIant it.
And this time we'II take care of it,
I promise.
I Iove you so much, Grandad.
I'II aIways Iove you.
Let's go to the oIive grove, Dad.
I feeI too ashamed.
No right to be there.
I have no right...
Can you imagine what Iife
wiII be Iike in 2,000 years?
Let's see if we can do it
a IittIe better this time.
THE OLIVE TREE
Please rate this subtitle at %url%
Help other users to choose the best subtitles